So you've learned all this, I
shall Gitt tools to manage your
personal projects. In this
section, we'll be talking about
various tools that you need to
master to collaborate with
others. We'll start off by
talking about the most common
collaboration workflows. Then
we're going to talk about
pushing, fetching and pulling
objects from remote
repositories. Next, we'll talk
about the essential
collaboration tools on GitHub.
The most popular Git hosting
platform will cover pull
requests, issues, and
milestones. And finally, we'll
talk about contributing to open
source projects. The tools we're
going to cover in this section
are super important. You'll be
using them every single day when
working with a team. So let's
jump in and get started.