By default, the push command
doesn't transfer our tags to a
remote repository, we have to
explicitly push them. So let's
create a new tag called version
1.0. This tag is added to the
last commit. Let's verify it
real quick. Okay, so here's our
tag. Now this tag is only
available in this repository on
my machine. If I want to send
this to GitHub and share it with
other team members, I have to
type git push origin, v 1.0.
Alright, beautiful. Our tag is
now on GitHub. Let's verified
real quick. So I refresh the
page. Here we have one tag.
Let's click here. On this page,
we can see the list of all the
tags in this repository, we can
click a tag to see more details.
So we can see who has created
this tag when and over here, you
can see these assets that GitHub
automatically generated for us.
So we can download our entire
source code at this point in
time. This is very useful. If we
push this type by accident, we
can remove it using the push
command. So we type git push
origin, exactly like before, but
before the tag name, we type
dash dash, delete. This is going
to delete this tag from origin.
Take a look. All right, our tag
is gone. So back on GitHub, we
no longer have a tag. But this
tag is still in my repository.
So if I type git log, look, this
tag is still here. If we don't
need it here, we can simply type
Git tag dash D for delete v 1.0.