One of the GitHub features that
goes hand in hand with tags is
release management, we can
create a release to package our
software along with source code,
binary files and release notes.
Let me show you. So here on the
homepage of our repository, we
go to tags, and then we go to
the releases tab. Currently, we
don't have any releases. So
let's create a new release. Now
over here, we can find an
existing tag or create a new
tag. Currently, we don't have
any tags. So I'm going to type v
1.0. When I create this release,
GitHub will automatically add
this tag to the latest commit.
Next to that, we have our target
branch, which is master. Here,
we give our release a title, we
can use the same value, version
1.0. Now in this box, we can
type our release notes. For
example, we can type a high sign
to add a title and say release
notes. And then using hyphens,
we can add bullet points. For
example, we can say, fixed bug
one fixed bug to either the form
data. Now we can preview our
changes. So here are our release
notes. Beautiful. Now, over
here, we can attach binary
files, so we can include the
compiled version of our
application. Now, if this
release is not production ready,
if it's not stable, we can tick
this box. This is a pre release.
And finally, we click on Publish
release. Alright, here's our
first release, we can see our
release notes, along with this
assets that GitHub automatically
generated for us included binary
files, like the compiled version
of our application, those binary
files would also be listed here.
Okay. Now over here, you can see
this release is based on this
tag, v 1.0, which is added to
the last commit in our
repository. Here, we also have a
label saying this is the latest
release of this repository. If
you made a mistake, you can
always delete this release. So
to the right side of this page,
which is not currently in my
recording, we know we have two
buttons, edit, release, and
delete. Now, back to the
homepage of our repository. Here
on the right side, you can see
all the releases. So this is all
about release management and
GitHub. Just remember, this is
not a good feature. It's a
GitHub feature. It's a high
level feature built on top of
tags