So far, we've been doing all the
work on master. Now let's talk
about working with branches. So
similar to tags, our branches
are private or local by default.
So if you want to collaborate
with other team members using a
branch, we have to explicitly
push that branch the same way we
push tags. So I'm going to
create a new branch called
feature slash Change Password.
Now, this is a private branch in
my local repository. It doesn't
exist on GitHub. So if we run
git push, we get this error
saying the current branch has no
upstream branch. This basically
means that this branch is not
linked to a branch in origin. So
Git is suggesting to run this
command to solve the problem.
But before doing so, let's run
git branch dash vv. So look,
here we can see our local and
remote tracking branches. So
Master, which is a local branch
is linked to origin slash
master. But features change
password is not linked to a
remote tracking branch. Now to
see all the remote tracking
branches, we can type git branch
dash R. So currently, we have
only these two pointers, origin
slash head and origin slash
master. So to link this private
branch to a branch in origin,
the first time you want to push
it, you have to type git push,
dash you that is the short form
offset upstream and then we type
the remote in this case, origin,
followed by the name of the
branch, so feature slash Change
Password. Alright, beautiful,
our branches pushed, we can
verify on GitHub. So let's
refresh this page. Now we have
two branches. And here's our new
branch. The back to the
terminal. If I type git branch
dash vv, you can see that this
local branch is now linked with
this remote tracking branch
origin slash feature slash
Change Password. Also, we can
look at all the remote tracking
branches. So now we have a new
remote tracking branch. Perfect.
Now we can start working with
this branch the same way we work
with Master so we can make new
commits here and then push them
to origin. At some point when
you're done, we want to remove
this rat. To do that we type git
push that previously we use
Dashiell and now we're going to
use dash D for delete. Then we
type the remote followed by the
branch name, feature slash
Change Password. Now this branch
is deleted from origin, we can
verify it right here. So
refresh, we only have a single
branch. Now let's type git
branch dash our our remote
tracking branch has gone
beautiful. But what if we type
git branch dash vv, we still
have this local branch that is
linked to origin slash feature
slash Change Password. But right
in front of this remote tracking
branch we have gone. So even
though we removed this branch
from origin, our local branch is
still there. So if we type git
branch, we can see it's right
here. And we're currently on
this branch so we cannot delete
it. So we have to switch to
master and then type git branch
dash D feature slash Change
Password. So this is how we can
create and delete branches in a
remote repository. Next, I'm
going to walk you through a real
collaboration scenario using
branches