Let me walk you through a real
collaboration scenario using
branches. So let's say Amy and I
are going to work on a feature
together. So one of us should
create a feature branch and push
it to GitHub. That is one way.
But there is another way, we can
create a branch directly on
GitHub. So in this drop down
list, we can view all of our
branches. And we can also create
a new branch. So I'm going to
call this feature slash, change
password, enter. Alright, now we
have a new branch. And this
branch is currently selected in
this repository. Look over here,
this branch is even with Master.
So as we push to this branch, we
can see how far this branch is
ahead of master. This is very
useful. Now back in the
terminal, I'm going to run git
fetch to get this new branch. So
we got a new branch called
feature slash change password,
we also got a new tag, that is
the tag that we created earlier
in the section. Now, let me show
you something. If we type git
branch, we only see master what
what happened to our new branch.
Well, let's run git branch dash
R. Look over here, we have a
remote tracking branch. So when
we ran fetch, we only got a
remote tracking branch. Now we
should create a private branch
in our local repository that
maps to this remote tracking
branch. So we type Git switch, I
say, we're going to call this
feature slash Change Password.
Now we want this branch or this
pointer to be at the same
location as a remote tracking
branch. So origin, slash feature
slash change, password. All
right, beautiful. Get a saying
that this new branch is set up
to track the remote branch from
origin. Perfect. So here on my
machine, I can add new commits
to this branch, and then push
them to origin. Now I'm going to
switch to another terminal
window to simulate Amy's
workspace. So here's Amy's
workspace, Amy is going to start
by cloning this repository. So
we go over here, grab the URL of
our repository. Good. Now we
type git clone. Alright, let's
go to this repository. So here
on the Amos workspace, if we
type git branch, once again, we
don't have that feature branch.
So Amish will also create a
private branch that maps to that
remote branch. So Git switch
dicey features slash change
password, this branch should be
based on origin, slash feature,
slash Change Password. Great.
Now on behalf of Amy, I'm going
to make a commit, and then push
it to GitHub. So something
really simple we can Aiko
password, to find one, then make
a commit, and say update five
one, then we do a push. So git
push. Beautiful, let's verify
that we have this new commit on
GitHub. So here on the homepage
of our repository, we can see
this message feature slash
Change Password had recent
pushes one minute ago, here, we
have a button for comparing and
creating a pull request. Let's
not worry about it yet. We'll
talk about it soon. Instead,
let's go to the list of our
commits. So currently, we have
four commits, these are the
commits on master. Let's change
this to our feature branch. So
here's the new commit that I
just pushed beautiful. So Amy
and I are going to keep pushing
to this branch. And in the
meantime, we have to pull each
other's changes. And if there
are conflicts, we have to
resolve them and then do another
push. Now at some point, this
feature is going to be complete.
Let's say I'm the person
responsible for closing this
branch. So on my machine, first,
I have to bring in Amy's changes
set around good, cool. All
right, we have a fast forward
beautiful, let's have a look at
our history. So git log, one
line all graph, take a look at
our feature branch is one commit
ahead of master. So we have to
merge this branch into master.
That is very easy, we switch to
master and then run git merge
feature slash Change Password.
Good. Once again, we have a fast
forward merge, because this is a
very simplified example, in a
real case scenario, most likely
will have conflicts. But I'm not
gonna repeat that here because
we already talked about
resolving conflicts. Now, let's
look at our log again. Look, now
Master, and feature slash Change
Password are pointing to the
same commit. However, origin
slash master is one commit
behind master. So here, we have
to do a push to send the final
changes to GitHub. So I'm
currently on Master, I run git
push. Alright, our changes are
now in GitHub. Let's look at our
log one more time.
So Master, and origin slash
master are now at the same
location. Beautiful. Now here on
GitHub, we have five commits.
Let's have a quick look here. So
here are the commits on master
Obviously, we have to commit
that was for implementing the
Change Password feature. So
we're done with this feature,
now should close this branch. So
I'm going to type git push dash
D origin, feature slash change
password, I'm going to remove
this branch from origin, as well
as its remote tracking branch in
my local repository. Good. Now
let's look at our branches. We
still have this local branch, we
don't need it anymore. So let's
remove it here as well. git
branch dash D, feature slash
Change Password. Beautiful. So
on my machine, I only have the
master branch. Let's look at our
remote tracking branches as
well. git branch dash R. Okay,
we no longer have that remote
tracking branch. Perfect. Now
what about Amy? Well, she is
still on the feature branch. So
on behalf of Amy, first wishes,
switch to master. Now we should
do a pull to bring in the merge
changes that much pushed. So
good pull. Good. So now both Amy
and I have the same history. Now
let's look at our branches. We
still have the private feature
branch. So let's delete it real
quick. Good. Now what about our
remote tracking branches? So if
we type git branch, that's our
look, we still have this remote
tracking branch. Even though
this branch is remote from
origin. To remove the tracking
branches that are not under
remote, we type Git remote prune
origin. Now look, this remote
tracking branch origin slash
feature slash change password is
pruned. So if you run git branch
dash R, we no longer see that
remote tracking branch. So this
is how two or more people can
collaborate on a feature