Quite often as part of
implementing a feature or fixing
a bug, we would like other team
members feedback about our code.
This is where we use pull
requests. With a pull request,
we essentially open a discussion
the team before merging and
branch into Master, let me walk
you through a real scenario.
Let's say Amy is going to
implement a new feature. So here
on Amy's machine, I'm going to
start a new branch, add a commit
to it, and then push it to
GitHub. So Git switch,dash C
feature slash login, Dallas,
Echo Hello, two, file three dot
txt stays the file, make a
comment and say, write hello to
file three. Now let's push this
branch. So git push the first
time we should use doshu. To set
the upstream branch. We're going
to push this to origin and call
it feature slash login. Now I
need to enter my credentials
because the cache has expired.
All right, beautiful. Now here
on GitHub, we see this message
feature slash login had recent
pushes one minute ago, we can
compare and create a pull
request. Alternatively, we can
go to the pull request tab and
create a new pull request from
here. On this page, we have to
select two branches, the base
branch, which is often Master,
and the target branch, which is
our feature branch. So before
merging this branch into Master,
we want to start a pull request
or a discussion of the team.
Now, because we're dealing with
a simple change, only a single
commit and no conflicts, we can
see that we can automatically
merge the changes. Quite often
that's not the case, we often
have conflicts that we have to
resolve. We'll talk about that
later. Now over here, we can see
the summary of changes. So we
have one commit, one file
change, zero comments and one
contributor. Here's the command
that we just pushed, right hello
to five three. Over here, we can
see the summary of changes. So
we are this line in five, three
dot txt. Beautiful. Now, let's
go ahead and create the pull
request. In this case, because
we have a single commit, GitHub
used our commit message as the
title for this pull request, I'm
going to change this to
something more descriptive. So
we're implementing a new
feature. for social login, we
want to allow the user to login
via Facebook. So social login,
that's better. Here, we can
write some details about this
pull request, and see if there
are things that we want other
people to review. Specifically,
we can list them here. Now let's
go ahead and create this pull
request. All right, here's our
pull request. Beautiful. It's
saying Code with Mosh wants to
erge one commit into master
rom feature slash login. Now,
et's say I'm Amy, so I'm going
o add mosh as a reviewer. So
ver here, here, we can see all
he collaborators in this
roject. Earlier in this
ection, I told you how to add
ollaborators. So I'm going to
dd mosh yet. Now we have a
ellow icon here saying we are
waiting request a review from
osh hamadani. So Mosh is goi
g to get an email saying ame
is your review. Now I'm goi
g to open another browser win
ow on behalf of Mosh. Alri
ht, here's Mosh's screen. On thi
page, we're going to go to pul
requests. We have one open p
ll requests. So let's take a
look. Look at this messag
. Code with Mosh request
d your review on this pull re
uest. So I can go ahead and add
my review. Now this box pops un
er this button review changes
I find this confusing, so I al
ays like to click away to clos
it and get back to it later.
ere we can see the summary
of all the changes. So in this
case, we have a single file fi
e, three, and we have this ne
line in this file, we can add
comments to individual lines b
clicking on this icon. I can s
y this line is good, but it's be
ter. If you capitalize, ah, of
ourse, I can write a rich re
iew using bold and italic
tuff. But let's not worry a
out it. So let's start our rev
ew. So I added one comment
to this line of code. And of
ourse I could add many more co
ments. Now I'm going to finish
y review and write a general
description saying please
ake these changes and do another
push. I can mark this as comment
I can approve this pull request
or I can request more changes
I'm going to request more ch
nges and submit my review.
Good. Now we are on the convers
tion tab, we can see the timelin
of things that have happene
. So initially, Amy started
this pull request with his det
ils. Here's the initial commit,
right hello to five three,
hen Amy or this gets called
ith multiple requests that a
eview and then Mosh Hamedani
requested changes. And here are
the details about this changes.
So the general comment, as well
s comments the individu
l lines of code. Also over her
we see this red icon can't sing
much hamadani requested changes.
Now back on Amy's machine, let's
make a change and do another
push. So I'm going to echo Hello
with a capital H 253 dot txt,
then I'm going to stage and
commit all the changes, say
capitalize, hello, then let's do
a push. So Amy did a push. Now
back on GitHub, she can come
over here and request Mosh to
eview the code again. So this
ill send Mosh a new n
tification and you email, B
lla, come back here and see t
is message one more time code w
th Mosh request said your re
iew on this pull request. So I
an add my second review. Once ag
in, I like to click away and se
the updated code. So I think th
s is great. I'm going to take th
s file as reviewed. And then su
mit my final review. So I'm go
ng to say everything looks pe
fect. Let's go ahead with me
ging. And then I can select ap
rove and submit the review. Al
ight, the changes are ap
roved beautiful. Now up here on
the conversation tab. Next to th
s reviewer. Now we have a ti
k so we can go ahead with me
ging. To do that. Go down be
ow, and we have this button me
ge pull request. Here's a qu
stion who should merge this pu
l request? Well, there are tw
opinions. Some teams believe th
t the person who started a pu
l request should not be able to
close it, the pull request wi
l always be close by someone el
e. Otherwise, these pull re
uests are meaningless. Anyone ca
start and close them. But th
re's also a different opinion ou
there. Some people argue th
t the person who started a pu
l request knows about that is
ue the most. So when it comes to
merging, most likely we're go
ng to have conflict, it's re
lly helpful to have that pe
son on board. So they argue th
t the person who opens a pull re
uest should be the one cl
sing it as well. So there's re
lly no right or wrong, it re
lly depends on your team's cu
ture. Now, here we have a few op
ions. We can create a merge co
mit, we can squash on merge, or
we can rebase and merge. We co
ered all these options be
ore. So I'm going to go with a
imple merge commit. All ri
ht, our pull requests su
cessfully merged and closed. No
we can delete this branch. Go
d. If you made a mistake, we ca
always come back here and re
tore the branch back on his ma
hine, let's switch to master an
then do a pool.
Beautiful. Now let's look at the
history.
Alright, so this last commit
over here is our merge commit
merge pull request number one
from Code with Mosh slash
feature slash login. Both my
master and origin slash master
are pointing to the same commit,
we no longer need this feature
branch. So we should delete this
local branch as well as the
remote tracking branch. We
already removed this branch from
GitHub. So now we need to remove
it from this repository. To do
that we type Git remote prune
origin. As I told you before,
this removes the branches that
don't exist on the remote in
this case origin. So now if we
type git branch dash R, we don't
have that remote tracking branch
beautiful. Finally, we need to
remove our local branch so git
branch dash D feature slash log