Now what if you have conflicts
when merging and closing a pull
request? Well, once again on his
machine, I'm going to start a
new branch, add a commit, push
it, create a pull request. And
in the meantime, I'm going to
create a conflict and change on
master. So when we merge this
branch into Master, we get a
conflict. So let's create a new
branch called feature slash, log
out. Now on this branch, I'm
going to write hello to file one
dot txt. Let's commit the
changes and say write hello to
file one. Now let's push this
branch. So push that shoe origin
feature slash logout. Now on
GitHub, we have this new branch
feature slash logout, we can
start a pull request. But before
doing so let's add a conflict
and change in master. So back to
Amy's machine. Let's switch to
master and write something
different to find one. So I'm
going to write world two file
one dot txt. Now let's commit
the changes, right world to find
one, and then do a push. Of
course, this doesn't have to
happen on a machine, someone
else might have a pull request
that is open, that pull request
might get merged into master. So
master can move forward without
me being aware of that. Okay,
either way, we have a conflict
and change. So let's go ahead.
Now let's say Amy has finished
her work. So she wants to start
a pull request. So over here, we
click on compare and pull
request. Now look, GitHub is
saying that it cannot
automatically merge the changes
because we have conflicts. But
don't worry, we can still create
the pull request. So let's give
it the title, feature logout and
I'm going to leave out the
description doesn't really
matter. All right, now we have a
pull request. At some point in
the future, we want to merge and
close this pull request. Now
look over here. GitHub is saying
this branch has conflicts that
must be resolved. So here we
have two options, we can use the
command line or use the GitHub
user interface. If you want to
use the command line, the
process is exactly like before.
So someone who is in charge of
merging, it could be Amy or
someone else. And that person
first has to pull in the latest
code, then they have to start
the merge process, they're gonna
get conflicts and they'll
resolve the conflicts, add a new
commit, and then push it to
GitHub. Exactly like before,
nothing different. So in this
lesson, I'm going to show you
how to resolve conflicts on
GitHub. That is very simple. So
we click on resolve conflicts.
Now on this page, we can see all
the conflict in files on the
left and this case, we have a
single file and on the right we
can see our conflict markers.
You have seen these before. So
in this branch feature slash
logout, we have added Hello, on
this branch on Master, we have
added world, so we need to
decide what changes we need. In
this case, I'm going to bring
the changes in both these
branches. So let's delete the
markers. You're left with hello
world. If you have multiple
conflicts, we can browse through
them using these buttons. Now,
let's mark this as resolved.
Good. So now we need to commit
the changes onto feature slash
logout. So commit. Good. Now
back to our pull request. Down
below, we no longer have that
message sent or conflict. So we
can go ahead and merge the pull
request. Done