One of the features of GitHub
that goes hand in hand with pull
requests is issue tracking. So
here on the issues tab, we can
track all kinds of issues like
bug fixes, new features,
enhancements, or any kind of
ideas we want to discuss in the
team.
So let me walk you through a
real example. I'm going to
create a new issue.
We give it a descriptive title,
like, send email on someone
signs up. Here, we can write
more details about this issue,
we can also attach files, this
is very useful, it's much easier
than tossing emails around. So
all the details we're working on
an issue are encapsulated in a
single place. Here, we can
optionally assign this issue to
one or more people, if we know
ahead of time. If not, people
can come in and assign issues to
themselves. In this case, I'm
going to assign this issue to
myself. Okay. And we can also
add labels to this issue. So
every Git repository has these
labels by default. We have bug
documentation, duplicate
enhancement, and so on. We can
also customize these labels.
I'll show you how to do that in
the next lesson. So let's add
enhancement. Now, let's go ahead
and submit a new issue. All
right, here's our issue. On this
page, we can have a conversation
about this issue. So anyone in
the team can come in and leave
comments. This is very useful.
Now one thing that I love here
is that we can link this issue
with a pull request. With this,
when we merge and close a pull
request, this issue will be
automatically closed, we can
also assign this issue to a
milestone, I'm going to talk
about that later in the section.
If this issue is not linked to a
pull request, we can always come
in here and close this issue
manually. Now, let's go back to
the list of issues. So we have a
single issue here. That is an
enhancement, you can immediately
see that I am working on this
issue. This is very useful in
teams. So anyone can come in
here and see who is working on
what. And if someone doesn't
have any work to do, they can
always come in here and pick an
issue. So I can come in here and
assign this issue to myself if
it's not assigned to someone
else. Now let's go back. Here we
can filter the list by author,
label project milestones
assignees. And we can also sort
the result in different ways.
I'm not going to go through
these they're really simple, you
can figure them out on your own.
Next I'm going to show you how
to customize the list of labels.