Let's see how we can customize
the list of labels in a GitHub
repository. So here on the
issues tab, we go to labels. On
this page, we can see all the
default labels that exist in
every GitHub repository. We can
create a new label, let's say
refactoring. We can optionally
give it a description and a
color. If you don't like this
color, you can click here,
GitHub automatically generates a
new color that is reflected over
here. Now let's create the
label. Good. Now look over here.
For the enhancement label. We
have one open issue or pull
request. So this is also another
useful report. We can see all
the labels and the number of
open issues assigned to them in
one place.