Now let's talk about milestones.
We use milestones to track the
progress of various issues. So
we can add a bunch of issues to
a milestone, and then see how
much we have progress in that
milestone. So here on the issues
tab, we go to milestones and
create a new milestone, we give
it a title. This can be anything
that is meaningful to the team.
For example, if you're working
on version two of our software,
the title can be 2.0 point oh,
now optionally, we can give it a
due date. So I'm going to set
this to, let's say, 30th of
September 2020. We can also give
it a description, and then
create the milestone. So here we
have one open milestone that is
due by September 30. Now over
here, you can see the progress
of this milestone. Currently, we
don't have any issues or
scientist milestone. So let's go
to the issues page and select
this issue. And of course, we
could select multiple issues,
and then put them in a
particular milestone. Good. Now,
look over here. This issue is
assigned to our version two
milestone. Now let's go to the
milestones tab. Now look over
here, we have one open issue
zero closed, and we're at zero
percent complete. If I close
this issue, our milestone will
be complete. Let me show you
real quick. So we go to the
issues. I'm going to select this
issue and then mark it as
closed. Okay, good. Now back to
the milestones page. Look at our
milestone is complete. This is a
very useful report.