So we have covered all the
essential collaboration tools.
Now let's see how we can work on
an open source project. For this
demo, I'm looking at this
repository with Vidly suite 5in
my personal GitHub account, le
's say you want to contribute
to this repository, perhaps
ou found a bug, or want
to implement a new feature. So
ou come to the issues tab, you
an create a new issue and descr
be the bug or the feature you w
nt to implement. Or you can p
ck one of the existing issu
s. Currently, there are 79, o
en issues here. Here's the probl
m, you don't have push access
to this repository, only I can p
sh to it. So what you need to do
is you go to the top and fork t
is repository. When you fork t
is repository, GitHub will tak
a complete copy of this reposit
ry and put it in your account,
ou have full control over t
at repository, you can create
ew branches, new tags, you can p
sh your stuff, you can do anyth
ng you want, right. So current
y, I'm logged in using my ot
er GitHub account, that is C
de with Mosh account, I'm going
o fork this repository that is
n my personal account, take
a loo
It's gonna take a few seconds.
All right, look, we have a copy
of this repository in my code
with Mosh account, which is
orked from my personal account.
o this is my repository and
itHub. Now, I'm going to clone
t on my local machine and start
orking on it. So let's go to
ode, grab the URL, and then
lone this repository. Good. So
ow let's go to this directory.
'm going to start a new branch,
it switch dash c, we can call
t buck fix. Now on this branch,
'm going to make a commit. So
et's echo hello to our README
ile, and then make a commit and
ay update README. Good. Now I'm
oing to push this branch to my
itHub repository. So git push
ashiell the first I'm going to
ush this branch origin, which
epresents my fork to
epository, and then the name of
he branch. That is bug fix.
ow, back on GitHub, my bug fix
ranch has recent push us. So
hen I'm done with this branch,
can start a pull request. Now
ook over here, we're trying to
ompare that bug fix branch and
his forked repository in my
ode much account. But comparing
hat with Master of this base
epository that is in my
ersonal account. So starting a
ull request is exactly like
efore, the only difference that
e have here is that we have two
epositories, the base
epository, which is the main or
he official repository, and my
ork repository. Now, we should
ive this Pull Request a
escriptive title. So we can say
ug fix, and change password
or, of course, we can leave
ore details, and then create
he pull request. Now the
aintainer of this repository,
n this case, myself is going to
et notified. So I'm going to
ome back here and have a
onversation with the person who
uggested these changes. So just
ike before, we can have a
onversation and the maintainer
an request changes, and the
ontributor can push new
ommits. At some point, when the
aintainer is happy, they can
ome over here and merge this
ull request. Here's the
nteresting part. Currently, I'm
ogged in using my code wash
ccount. So I'm a contributor to
his repository. Now look, I
annot merge and close this pull
equest, only the maintainer can
o this. So on this other
rowser window, I'm logged in
sing my personal account. And
ook, we have four pull
equests. And here's the last
ne that I just created using my
ther account. So I can look at
his pull request. Go through
hanges with the contributor. At
ome point when I'm happy, I can
erge and close this pull
equest.