So at the beginning of the
course, I told you that version
control systems fall into two
groups, centralized and
distributed. In centralized
systems like subversion, you
have a single repository that is
shared by all team members. The
problem with this system is that
everyone is dependent on this
central repository. If the
server that is hosting this
repository goes offline, no one
can commit or view the project
history. In distributed systems
like git, every developer has a
repository on their machine. So
they're not dependent on a
central server, they can work
offline with their local
repository. But how can we
collaborate with this model?
Well, we can synchronize our
work directly with each other.
But this is often too complex
and error prone. Instead, we can
use what we call the centralized
workflow. So everyone has their
local repository, but there's
also a central repository they
used to synchronize their work.
This is the workflow used in
most private teams and closed
source projects. But you might
be asking, Hey, Mosh, what is
the point of this workflow? How
is it better than a centralized
version control system like
subversion? Well, with this
model, we don't have a single
point of failure, we can work
with our local repository. And
if a central repository is
unavailable for a period of
time, we can synchronize our
work directly. Now, where should
we put the central repository,
so it's accessible to all team
members? Well, some
organizations put this
repository on a server in their
private network. Others prefer
to use Git hosting services like
GitHub, git lab, Gitbucket, and
so on. With all these services,
we can set up a repository as a
private repository. So it's only
accessible to our team and no
one else. So let's walk through
a real scenario. John and Amy
want to collaborate on a
project. They start off by
cloning or taking a copy of this
central repository. And now they
both have a local repository on
their machine. So John starts
working and makes a few commits,
me could be making other commits
In the meantime, but let's not
worry about that yet. Now, at
some point, john needs to share
his work with Amy. To do that,
he uses the push command to send
his commits to the central
repository. The central
repository is now in sync with
John's work. Now, Amy can use
the pull command to bring in
John's work into her local
repository. If John's work
conflicts with Amy's work, she
has to resolve the conflicts and
then push our changes to the
central repository. So this is
the centralized workflow, which
is used in most private teams,
everyone in the team has pushed
access to right to the central
repository, we have another
workflow for open source
projects called integration
manager workflow. In an open
source project, we have one or
more maintainers, and many
contributors. The problem is
that we don't know this
contributors. So we cannot trust
them enough to give them push a
write access to our repository,
only the maintainers of the
project have pushed access to
the project repository. So if
you want to contribute, first,
we should fork the project
repository to get a copy of this
repository in the cloud. Next,
we clone this repository to get
a local copy on our machine, we
make a few commits, and when
we're ready to share our work,
we do a push to send our commits
to our forked repository. Next,
we send a pull request to the
maintainer of the project. This
is a feature built into
platforms like GitHub, I'll show
you how to do that later in this
section. So the maintainer of
the project gets notified, then
they can pull in our changes,
review them. And if they're
happy, they can merge our work
into their local repository, and
then push the merge changes to
the official repository. This is
called the integration manager
workflow. Because someone is in
charge of integrating changes,
we cannot push directly to this
official repository. That's why
we have to fork it to get a copy
in the cloud. Because this
repository is in the cloud. It's
also visible to the maintainer
of the project, and that's how
they can pull in our changes.
Alright, that's it for
workflows. Next, we're going to
create a GitHub repository to
see this workflows in action.