So here's the repository for an
open source project, we fork
this repository to contribute to
it. Now there is a problem. This
forked repository is not
connected to the original or the
base repository. So from time to
time, it can get out of sync
with the base repository. If
other people contribute to the
base repository and add new
commits to the master branch, we
are not going to be aware of
those new commits. In this
lesson, I'm going to show you
how to keep this forked
repository up to date. So in
this local repository on our
machine, we have a reference to
our forked repository called
origin. Right, we can add
another reference to the base
repository, and then use the
pull command to bring in the new
commits. And then we can push
them to our forked repository.
As simple as that. Let's see
this in action. Earlier, we
briefly talked about the remote
command. With this command, we
can manage the remote
repositories. So currently, we
have a single remote that is
origin, we can run git remote
dash V, that is short for
variables to see more details
about these remote repositories.
So here, we have two channels,
fetch for getting the objects
and push for pushing objects,
both these channels are mapped
to this URL. Now to add a new
remote, we type Git remote add,
we give it a name, like base, or
a lot of people like to call it
upstream, you can call it
whatever you want, it doesn't
really matter. Now wanted to
grab the URL of the base or the
original repository. So here on
my personal GitHub account,
here's our Villa repository, I'm
going to grab the URL, and then
paste it over here. Good. Now,
let's look at our remote
repositories. So we have origin
and upstream. Once again, we can
run remote dash v. So you can
see origin is pointing to Bitly
in my Code with Mosh account,
hereas upstream is pointing to
it name, in my personal
ccount, okay. Now, let's say we
ade a mistake, and we want to
ename this remote repository.
e simply type Git remote
ename, and we want to rename
pstream to base that's better.
f you're done with a remote, we
an simply remove it, we type
it remote, RM, and then we type
he name. Alright, so we're done
ere. Now I'm going to go to my
riginal or the base repository,
nd make a new commit. So here
n my personal account, I'm
oing to edit this README file.
o let's add a new line of code
nd then make a commit. Good. So
e added a new commit to the
aster branch of the base
epository. Now I'm going to
witch to my forked repository.
ow on my code with my account,
ook over here, GitHub is saying
hat this branch, our master
ranch, is one commit behind the
aster of the base repository.
o back in the terminal, we need
o use the fetch or the pull
ommand to bring in the new
ommits. So I'm going to use
etch for now, the earlier the
ection, we use the fetch
ommand, without specifying the
ame of the remote, I told you
hat if we don't supply the name
f the remote, by default,
rigin will be assume. Now in
his case, we don't want to
etch the commits from origin,
ecause that is a forked
epository, we want to get the
ew commits from the base
epository. So here we type
ase. Good. So we got a new
ranch called base slash master.
ow let's look at our history.
o here's our local master
ranch. And here's the master
ranch of the base repository.
o our local master is behind
he master of the base
epository. So we should merge
ase slash master into our local
aster. So first, we switch to
aster and then run git merge
ase slash master. Now, in this
ase, because the local master
s not diverged from the remote
aster, we're going to have a
ast forward merge, take a look.
here you go. Fast forward. Now,
et's look at the history one
ore time. Okay, so now our
ocal master and base slash
aster are pointing to the same
ommit beautiful. So our local
epository is in sync with the
ase repository. Now I'm going
o push the changes into our
orked repository. So git push.
ow, back on my Code with Mosh a
count on GitHub, when I r
fresh the page, this notice is g
ing to go away. Take a look. N
w, GitHub is saying that this b
anch is even with the master o
the base repository, b
autiful. So this is how we can k
ep a fork repository up to d
te. Now back to the terminal, i
's always a good practice to m
rge the master branch into y
ur local feature branch, b
cause this will reduce the c
ance for conflicts in the f
ture. If there are changes in t
e master that will affect your w
rk. You want to make sure that y
ur work is on top of those c
anges. So we're going to s
itch to our bug fix branch.
And then run git merge Master,
we're going to bring in the
changes in master into the
current branch. That look, we
have a conflict. So by resolving
the conflicts locally at this
point in time, we'll reduce the
chance for future conflicts when
the maintainer of the project
wants to merge and close our
pull requests.