Let's see how we can work with
remote repositories here in VS
code. Unfortunately, we have
limited collaboration tools here
compared to GitKraken. But let
me walk you through the tools we
have here real quick. So we go
to GitLens. We talked about this
earlier in the course, we can
right click on our repository.
Here, we have fetch, pull, push,
and push for us. Now one thing
that I like about get Labs is
that it tells us how far we are
behind or ahead of a branch in
origin. So we're currently on
the bug fix branch, I'm going to
create a new commit, and then
GitLens. will tell us that we
are one commit ahead of origin
slash bug fix, take a look. So
I'm going to change our README
file and add a new line. Save.
Now, let's come in and say
update README. Good. Now, back
in GitLens. Take a look.
GitLens's saying, we have one
coming ahead, we can expand this
folder and see the commit that
we have to push to origin. So we
can click on this icon and push
this and here we have three
options. We can do a regular
push, we can do a force push or
cancel. And as I told you
before, you should not really
use a force push that often
unless you have screwed
something up. So let's go with a
regular push. Good. Now the
first time you're going to see
this pop up saying extension
GitHub wants to sign in using
GitHub. So let's allow that. Now
we have authorized visual city
code to access GitHub. Let's go
with that. And then confirm.
Here we have to enter our
password. Okay, perfect. Now,
back to VS code. It's saying
that GitHub authentication wants
to open a UI. That's totally
fine. Let's open it. Good. Now
we have this prompt here saying,
Would you like code to
periodically run git fetch, I
find this pretty useful because
it tells us how far we are
behind origin. So let's allow
that. Good. So we're done with
pushing. Now unfortunately, here
we cannot push tags or branches
at this not at the time of
recording this video. So to push
a branch or a tag, we have to go
back to the terminal. Another
tool we have here is remote. so
here we can see we have two
remote, base and origin. We can
add a new remote or rename or
remove an existing one. So these
are pretty much all the
collaboration tools we have in
GitLens, GitKraken is a lot
better. We'll look at that.
Next.