Let's look at the collaboration
tools and GitKraken. So cu
rently we are on the bug fix br
nch, we can right click this br
nch or any of the branches. He
e we have pull, push, instead up
tream. With sin upstream, we ca
map a local branch to a br
nch in a remote repository. He
e, unlike VS code, we can pu
h our branches and tags. So I'
going to create a new branch of
of master. So I'm going to ri
ht click this commit, which is
the last commit on master and th
n create a new branch called
feature.
Alright, now let's make a small
change and add a new commit to
this branch. So I'm going to go
to README file and write
something here. Save Now, let's
make a comment and say update
README. Good. So our feature
branch has moved forward. Now we
can push this branch
directly to our GitHub
repository. So right click and
push,
GitKraken is asking the name o
the remote branch. So I want t
accept the default value h
re. That is feature Submit. N
w the first time we want to p
sh, we have to get an a
thorization token. Here we h
ve three options, refresh t
ken, retry without auth. And c
ncel, I'm going to refresh my t
ken. Just like before, we have t
authorize GitKraken to acce
s GitHub. So let's continue
and confirm.
Good. Now back to GitKraken, we
push successfully beautiful, pu
hing tax is exactly the same. So
here on Master, I can right cl
ck and create a new tag. Le
's call that version 1.0.
Now, we can
right click this tag and push it
to a remote repository. Here we
have two remotes, base and
origin, we can push to one of
these repositories or to all of
them. So GitKrakenhas a lot mor
features than GitLens. Here,
we can also manage our remot
s. So on the left side, we curre
tly have two remotes, base and o
igin, we can add a new remot
, pretty straightforward. One m
re thing I love about GitKraken
is managing pull requests
So here we have another
anel for our pull requests
So here are all the pull req
ests we have in our base rep
sitory, we can easily create a
new pull request. So let's sa
we're done with this feature
ranch. Now we're going to start
a pull request, until the main
ainer of this project, bring ou
changes into the original
repository. So we right click th
s branch and then start a pull r
quest to base from origin s
ash feature. Take a look. So
we were starting a pull request
o merge the feature branch o
our forked repository into the
master of this base reposito
y. Just like before, we can give
this Pull Request a title, a
description,
and then create the pull
request.
Perfect, we're done.
Now here in the original or the
base repository, we can see our
new pull request. It's right
here.