In this section, we're going to
use GitHub, which is the most
popular Git hosting platform. So
it's going to host our central
repository in the cloud. If you
don't use GitHub in your
organization, that's perfectly
fine, you should still watch the
rest of this section to learn
how to collaborate with others.
So head over to github.com. If
you don't have an account,
create one, it's free and takes
only a few seconds, just make
sure to verify your email before
proceeding. So here, I'm logged
in, let's create a new
repository on the top. Right,
first, we give our repository a
theme. I'm going to call this
Mars, we can optionally give it
a description. Next, we should
decide if this repository is
going to be public or private.
If a mark this as public, anyone
on the internet can see this
repository, this is useful for
open source project. If we set
it as private, we choose who can
see and commit to this
repository. But to use a private
repository we have to pay. So
for this demo, I'm going to go
with a public repository. Next,
we can initialize this
repository with a readme file
with a git ignore file and a
license. I'm going to select
this README file over here. So
GitHub is going to add this file
and create the first commit for
us take a look. So create
repository. Here's a repository
and beautiful now look at the
URL github.com, slash your
username, slash your repository.
So anyone on GitHub can have
multiple repositories. Over
here, you can see the current
branch that is Master, we have
only one branch, and zero tags
In this box, we can see th
content of our project. S
currently, we have only a singl
file, that is a readme file, w
can click on this, to see it
content, pretty basic. Now let'
go back to the top we can se
the latest commit, that is th
initial commit that GitHu
created. Here's our commit ID
the date time it was submitted
and here we can see the tota
number of commits. So if w
click here, we can see a log o
all of our recent commits. s
here we can see the commits o
the master branch. If we ha
multiple branches, we coul
select them here to filter th
lock. Now to see more detail
about a command, we can click o
it. So you can see this commi
was submitted on the maste
branch. It was submitted by m
about five minutes ago. O
course, it actually happened
minute ago, but I had to paus
the recording. That is why Her
you can see a summary of th
changes in this commit. So w
have one change file with on
addition has zero deletions
That means we have added on
line in this file. Here's th
file we're talking about READ M
. And over here you can see a di
f of this file. Alright, now th
t we have a repository Next I
m going to show you how to a
d collaborators her