So even though this repository
is public, no one but me can
push array to it. Other people
can see my code and commit
history, but they cannot push
new commits. So if you work in a
team, you should add your team
members here and give them push
access. Let me show you how to
do this. So over here, we have a
tab on the right side, called
settings.
Here we go to manage access.
Now, look, currently, we don't
have any collaborators, we can
invite our team members by their
GitHub username, full name or
email. So I'm going to look
myself up. Here's my other
GitHub account. But please,
please, please don't invite me I
don't want to get 1000
notifications. Every time
someone watches this course I'm
just following along. So I'm
going to add myself. Now I have
an invitation that is pending.
So I'm going to get an email and
in that email, there is a link
for me to accept or decline the
invitation and once I accept the
invitation, then I'll have push
access to this repository.