So we have a GitHub repository
in the cloud. Now, every team
member should clone this
repository. That means they
should take a copy of this
repository and put it on their
machine. Locally, they will work
with that repository. And when
they're ready to share their
changes, they will push their
commits to this central
repository. Okay. So to clone
this repository, we go to the
code tab, here, we can see the
full URL of this repository.
Let's copy this, we go through
terminal and type git clone, and
paste the URL. When we execute
this command, Git is going to
create a directory by the same
name, the same name as our
repository. If you don't like
this name, you can always change
it. so here we can say, Mars
project, take a look. So git
clone our entire repository. So
all the commits in the central
repository also exist here on my
machine. Currently, we have only
a single commit. Now, let's go
to this directory, Mars project,
and run git log. So currently,
we have a single commit. Now
look at this pointers, we have
head pointing to master. And we
have these two pointers in red
origin slash master and origin
slash head. What are these?
Well, when we clone a
repository, get names the source
repository, in this case, the
one that we have on GitHub, get
names that origin. So origin is
a reference to that repository.
Origin slash master tells us
where is the master branch in
that repository, because now we
have multiple repositories, and
the history in each repository
can evolve independently. So
origin slash master tells us
where is the master branch in
our origin repository, that
technically this is called a
remote tracking branch. It's a
branch, but it's not a kind of
branch you are familiar with, so
we cannot check it out. We
cannot commit to it. So if you
type, git switch, origin slash
Master, we get an error. If you
type git branch, we can see we
only have a single branch, the
master branch. So origin slash
master is a remote tracking
branch. Similarly, origin slash
head tells us where's the head
pointer in our origin
repository. Here we have a
useful command, you should be
familiar with Git remote. This
shows the list of remote
repositories. A remote
repository is a repository that
is not on our machine more
accurately, it's not in the
current directory. So currently,
we have only a single remote
repository, that is our origin
repository. If we type Git
remote, dash V for verbose, we
can see more details about this
remote repository. So origin is
referencing this repository over
here github.com slash code with
Marsh slash Mars that get so
this is the URL that Git is
going to use when we talk to
this remote repository.