So here's the current situation.
On the left side, we have our
local repository. And on the
right side, we have our remote
repository, which is the
repository hosted by GitHub in
the cloud. Now, one thing to
understand here is that our
local repository is not
connected to the remote
repository. So if you have a new
commit in our remote repository,
our local repository will not be
aware of that. Here, we have to
use the fetch command to
download this new commit. So Git
is going to download this new
command. And then we'll origin
slash master forward. So as I
told you before, origin slash
master is a remote tracking
branch, and tells us where's the
master branch and origin. In
this case, it's pointing to B.
Even though we downloaded this
new commit, our working
directory is none updated.
Because currently master is
pointing to a, that is the
previous commit the previous
snapshot. So we don't have those
changes in our working
directory. Now, how can we bring
those changes here? Well, we
have two branches, doesn't
matter that one of them is a
remote tracking branch. And to
bring those changes into Master,
we have to merge the other
branch into master.
So
we switch to the master branch
and type Git merge, origin slash
master. Now in this case, our
branches haven't diverged. And
we have a direct linear path
from origin slash master to
master. So we're going to have a
fast forward merge. In contrast,
if our branches had diverged,
potentially, we could have a
conflict. So we'll have to
resolve the conflict just like
before, let's see this in
action. Here on GitHub, we can
go to Add File and create a new
file or upload files, we can
also edit existing files. So in
this demo, I'm going to edit our
README file and create a new
commit directly on this
repository. So let's click on
README file, and then we click
on this pencil icon. Now let's
add a new line of code, we can
preview our changes. So we're
adding this new line that is
indicated by green. And over
here, we can specify our commit
message. So by default, GitHub
is suggesting update README, we
can leave it as is, optionally,
we can add some description here
as well. Here, we have two
options, we can commit directly
to master. Or we can create a
new branch and start a pull
request. I'll talk about the
second option in the future. So
let's commit this directly on
master. And now, back on the
homepage of our repository. So
you can see we have two
commands, let's have a quick
look. Here's our new commit
update README. Now back in the
terminal, we don't have this new
commit in our local repository,
let me show you. So we type git
log. And, look, we only have
this commit over here, that is
the initial commit. So to
download new commands, we have
to type Git fetch. And then we
specify the remote, in this case
origin. and optionally, we can
specify a branch. So if you want
to download the commits on a
particular branch, we can type
the branch name here, if we
leave it out, we're going to
download all the comments in
that remote repository. If you
drop origin, get assumes that we
want to fetch the commits from
origin. So let's go with that.
Alright, we fetch the new
commit. Let's verify it. So
let's look at the log one more
time. See, our remote tracking
branch has moved forward. So now
we have this new command. But
this commit is not on our master
branch. So master is behind by
one commit. There is another
useful command you should be
familiar with. That is git
branch dash vv. It shows how our
local and remote tracking
branches are diverging. So our
master branch is linked to this
branch origin slash Master, and
it's behind by one commit. So
now we have to do a merge. So
we're currently on Master, we
type Git merge origin slash
Master, because our branches
haven't diverged. And we have a
direct linear path from this
target branch into Master, we're
going to have a fast forward
merge, take a look. There you
go. Fast forward. Now let's look
at the log one more time. So git
log. So Master, and origin slash
master are pointing to the same
commit. We can also verify this
using git branch dash vv. So we
no longer have that message, one
commit behind. Now we can look
at the content of a readme file
using the cat command. So cat
README, and
here's the new line that I added
on GitHub.
So this change is now in our
working directory.