So to bring the changes in a
remote repository into our local
repository, most of the time, we
have to do a fetch, followed by
a merge. So we have a command
that combines the two, it's the
pull command, let's see how it
works. So let's say our local
and remote repositories are in
the same state, we have a single
commit in both these
repositories. Now our
repositories are going to evolve
in different ways. So in our
local repository, we're going to
add this new commit beam. And in
our remote repository, we're
going to add this other commit,
see, so when we run git pull,
Git is going to download C and
put it into our local
repository, not that origin
slash master is pointing to see.
So now our branches have
diverged. In this case, Git is
going to perform a three way
merge to bring the remote
changes into our master branch.
Now, some people don't like
these merge commits, because
they pollute the history. So
alternatively, we can use
rebasing here, so I'm going to
undo the merge commit, we're in
the same state as before, if we
use the rebase option, Git is
going to rebase, our master
branch on top of origin slash
master. So what is the base of
our master branch, it's a when
we use the rebase option, and
Git is going to change the base
of our master from A to C. So
essentially, it's replaying our
local changes and on top of
changes made by others, with
this will end up with simple
nonlinear history. Now, which
approach is better? Well, it
depends who you ask. This has
been a discussion going for
years. Some people love rebasing
others prefer merge commits. Now
let's see this in action. So
once again, let's create another
commit on GitHub, I'm going to
edit the readme file and add yet
another line of code. Let's make
a commit. Good. So back into
terminal, I'm also going to make
a commit in master. So our local
and remote branches diverged. So
we can add a new file, file one,
then added committed at file on
good, let's have a quick look at
our log. So git log. So our
master branch is ahead of origin
slash master by one commit. But
at this point, we are not aware
of the commit we made on GitHub.
So if we run git pull, Git is
going to download the new commit
in our GitHub repository, and
then perform a three way merge
to bring those changes into our
master, take a look. So here's
the default message for our
merge commit, we're going to
accept it.
Now back in the terminal. Let's
look at the log one more time.
There you go. Here's our merge
commit that combines the changes
in origin slash master and
master. So we ended up with
nonlinear history. Here, we can
use rebasing to create linear
history. But before doing so,
I'm going to undo it this last
merge commit, so we end up in
the previous state. So we type
Git reset, dash dash heart, head
till the one. Okay, let's look
at our log. So we're in the
previous state before the merge
commit, our branches have
diverse. Now we can run git pull
rebase to replay our local
changes, in this case, adding
this file on top of the changes
in origin slash master. So we
type Git pull dash dash rebase.
Alright, now, let's look at the
log one more time. Now we have
simple linear history. This
commit that we have in master
for adding file one is added on
top of the last commit we made
on GitHub. Now look over here,
my terminal window is saying
that I have one commit to push
to origin. I'll show you how to
do that, next.