So in our local repository, our
master branch is of origin slash
master by one commit. So we can
use the push command to send
this new commit to origin. When
we run this command, git will
send our new commit to the
remote repository, then it will
move the master pointer forward
2.2 C. And finally it would move
origin slash Master 2.2 C as
well. So we type git push. Next,
we specified the remote
repository in this case, origin.
And finally, we specified the
branch we want to push master.
There, currently, we are on the
master branch so we can drop
master. Also, if a drop origin
is good, we'll assume origin by
default. So we just type git
push. Here, we have to enter our
GitHub credentials. So I'm going
to add my email
and password.
Good. So get sent our new coming
to origin. Let's verified real
quick. So here on GitHub, look,
we have four commands. And
here's the last commit that we
just pushed at file one. Now,
sometimes your push may get
rejected. Let's see why. So once
again, our local repository is
ahead of origin by one commit.
Now let's say before we do a
push, someone else does a push
an add a new commit to origin.
Now, if we do a push, our push
will get rejected, because our
histories have evolved
differently. So good prevents us
from overwriting someone else's
work, that I've seen some people
using the force option here,
this is a terrible thing you can
do with this, you're telling it
to drop other people's work, and
replace it with your work. This
is not what we want. So unless
you have a very strong reason
for using the force option, you
should never ever, ever, ever
use this option. Basically, you
should use this only if you have
screwed things up. So what can
we do here? Well, we have to do
a poll to bring other people's
work into our local repository.
And then we have to do a merge
or a rebase. If there are any
conflicts, we have to resolve
them, and then we can do a push.
Here's a question for you look
at the history of these two
repositories. What comments do
we have in our local repository
that don't exist in origin, C
and M, right? Because in both
these repositories, we have a, b
and d. So when we do a push, git
will send these two commits to
the origin. Now we have the same
state in both these
repositories. The final code and
the history of changes are
identical.