In the previous lesson, you saw
that when I tried to push my
commits, I had to enter my
GitHub credentials, my GitHub
username and password. Now we
don't enter our credentials
every time you want to do a push
that is too tedious and time
consuming. The good news is that
we can store our credentials in
memory or on disk, and tell Git
where to find it, all we have to
do is to set a configuration
value. So we type Git config,
dash dash global, we said
credential, that helper to it,
we set it to cash, it will store
our credentials for 15 minutes
in memory. If that's not
sufficient for you, and you want
to store your credentials per
Mac on disk. On Mac, you have to
use key chain. And on Windows,
you have to use Windows
credential store. These are both
storages for storing sensitive
data. So our credentials will
get stored in an encrypted way.
So if you're on Mac, first, you
have to find out if key chain
helper is installed or not. So
we type Git credential, dash OS
X key chain. As you can see,
kitchen helper is installed on
my machine. If it's not
installed on your machine, you
will see the instructions to
install it, it's very easy. Once
you install kitchen helper, then
you said Git config, dash dash
global credential, that helper
to OS X key chain, that's all
you have to do. If you're a
Windows user, you have to
install get credential manager
for Windows. So head over to
github.com slash Microsoft slash
get credential manager for
Windows. On this page, you can
find that installer is right
here. So download this and
follow the instructions.
Unfortunately, I don't have a
Windows machine to show the
process, but it should be very
easy. You shouldn't have any
problems.