In this section I'm going to
talk about one of the most
important and powerful features
of Git called branching. You
will learn how to use branches
to diverged from the main line
of development and work on
something else in isolation, how
to compare branches to see their
differences, how to merge them.
We'll talk about different
merging techniques like three
way merging, fast forwarding,
squash merging and rebasing.
We'll also talk about resolving
merge conflicts, undoing a
faulty merge, and using
essential tools like stashing
and cherry picking. The skills
you're going to learn in this
section can totally change the
way you develop software. So
let's jump in and get started.