So you've seen examples of
merging branches. Now in the
real world. Quite often when we
merge branches, we run into
conflicts, conflicts happen when
the same line of code has been
changed in different ways in two
branches, or if a given file is
changed in one branch, but it's
deleted in another branch, in
another scenario is when the
same file is added twice in two
different branches. But the
content of this file is
different. In this case, as Git
cannot figure out how to merge
the changes, so it will stop the
merge process. And that's when
we need to jump in and tell Git
how we want to proceed. Let me
show you a real example. So here
on the master, let's create a
new branch called bug fix slash,
Change Password. Now, let's open
Change Password. txt. Here on
the second line, let's say
change, and the bug fix branch,
save the changes, I can
determine all let's add this to
the staging area and commit it.
We can say update, change,
password, that txt. Of course,
this is another good commit
message, because it's tied to a
particular file. But it's fine
for this demo. So let's move on.
Alright, so we change this file
and this branch. Now let's
switch to the master branch, and
update the same file in a
different way. So let's open it.
Here on the second line, I'm
going to say change in the
master branch. All right, now,
back in the terminal, let's add
this first staging area, and
committed were the same commit
message. So now this file is
changed in different ways across
these two branches. So when we
run git merge, bug fix slash
change password, we get a
conflict, we get a merge
conflict, and Change Password
txt. So good stuff the merge
process, I know we have to jump
in and manually combine the
changes. Also, as you can see
over here, we are in the middle
of a merge process. So let's run
git status. Look under unmerged
paths, this is where we can find
the conflict of flats. So both
our branches have modified
change password or txt. Now,
this is a very simplified
example, in a real world
scenario, you might have more
than 10 files listed here.
Basically, the more your
branches diverged, the more
conflicts you're going to have.
We're going to talk about this
later in the section. For now,
let's just see what you need to
do when there is a conflict. So
we're going to open Change
Password. txt. Look what's going
on here. The first time I saw
this, I was like, What the hell
is going on here. But this is
very simple. Here we have
markers that represent the
changes in the current branch
and in the other branch. So over
here, we have this markers in
profit that we have had, which
points to the current branch in
this branch, which is the master
branch, we have introduced this
line. Now after this, we have
this divider, and below the
divider, we have to change this
in the other branch. So that is
the slide over here. And after
this, we have the marker for the
other Brach bug fix slash Change
Password. Now in a real
situation, you might have
multiple conflicts in the same
file. So for different chunks of
code, you're going to see these
markers. Now let's see what we
can do here. Here in VS code, we
have a few options, we can
accept the current change. If we
click this, all those markers
are gone. And we are left with
the change and the master
branch. Let's undo this.
Alternatively, we can accept the
incoming change. So once again,
all the markers are gone. I know
we have to change in the other
branch. Let's do this. Another
option is to accept both
changes. Let's ponder this
again.
So here are the options in VS
code. We also have third party
merge tools for handling
conflicts. We'll talk about that
in the next lesson. But before
we get there, let me show you a
different way of resolving
conflicts, we can manually edit
this file by hand and remove
this markers. So I'm going to
remove the head marker. Okay,
I'm also going to remove the
divider and the second marker.
So here we have changes in both
these branches. We can reorder
them. So we can put this one
first. So this is how we are
manually merging the changes
that just remember that Ideally,
you should not introduce new
code here. So here we should not
add a new line of code. Because
this line of code was not
introduced in any of these
branches. It's a new line that
you're adding in a merge commit.
If you do this, this merge
commit is referred to as an evil
commit, because it's introducing
changes that didn't exist in any
of these branches. The whole
point of a merge commit is to
combine changes across two
branches, right. So as much as
possible, try not to introduce
new changes here. But I know in
real world situations, sometimes
this is not avoidable. There are
cases where you need to manually
edit the changes and introduce
something new. Now let's delete
this line. Save the changes back
into terminal, we have to add
this file to the staging area.
Why? Because this is what we're
proposing for the next commit,
right? So now let's run git
status. We no longer have
unmerged paths, which means we
no longer have conflicts. So we
have modified this file, Change
Password. txt. Now be run git
commit, we can leave out the
message option and accept the
default message, merge branch
bug fix into master. So let's
close this.
Back in the terminal. We're done
with the merge.