Quite frankly, yes, good is not
the best tool for resolving
conflicts, at least not at the
time of recording this lesson.
So let's look at some other
tools for resolving conflicts.
There's so many tools out there.
The most popular ones are K,
diff, and P4merge, which are
cross platform, and winmerge,
which is for Windows only. If
you use GetKraken, or a powerful
Id like IntelliJ, you don't need
any of this external merge
tools. But they still encourage
you to watch this lesson to the
end, because the skills you're
going to learn will transfer to
other tools. In this lesson,
we're going to use p for merge
for resolving conflicts. So open
up your browser and search for
P4merge. Over here on
P4merge.com. You can download
the latest version. Let's go
with this. Here, you have to
select your operating system,
I'm going to go with Mac and
download the latest version. We
don't have to register. So let's
skip registration. Good. All
right, so we get a dmg file on
Mac. If you're on Windows,
you'll get a setup wizard. So
let's drag and drop before merge
onto applications. It seemed
that I already have this, so I'm
going to replace it with the
latest version. Good. Now here
in the terminal, we have to
configure P4merge as our default
merge tool. So we say Git
config, dash dash global merge
tool, we give it a name, P4merge
next we need to tell Git where
to find p for merge. So once
again, git config, dash dash
global merge tool dot P4merge,
that is the name we assigned
over here, dot path. Here in
double quotes, we should add the
full path to P4merge. If you're
on Windows, your path is going
to be like C colon, backslash
Program Files, backslas p for
P4merge, backslash, whatever,
depending on where you have
installed this. On Mac, the path
is going to be slash
applications, slash P4merge that
app slash contents slash Mac OS
slash P4merge make sure to spell
it properly, exactly as what you
see here. All the uppercase and
lowercase letters are different
because Mac OS is a case
sensitive operating system.
Okay, so we have configured our
default merge tool. Now we need
a merge conflict. To save time,
I'm not going to recreate
another merge conflict, I'm
going to simulate the previous
conflict. So we're on master.
And we want to merge this with
our bug fix branch. So Git
merge, bug fix slash Change
Password. Alright, we got to
merge conflicts exactly like
before. In the previous lesson,
we open change password in VS
code to edit the conflict here.
Now this time, we're going to
use our external merge tool. So
if we run git merge, so right
here, we have three copies of
our change password file. On the
left side, we have changed
password on the left remote.
This is the version we have in
our remote or target branch,
which is our bug fix branch. In
the middle, we have Change
Password underline base, this is
the base copy the base version.
So here's the version of this
file before our branches
diverged. And on the right side,
we have changed password
underlined local. So this
represents the changes we have
in the current branch, which is
the master branch. Now the
beauty of this tool is that here
we can visually see the
conflicting changes. So I like
VS code where we had those ugly
Git markers. Here, we can easily
see that on the second line, we
have a conflict and change. Now
down below, we can see how these
changes are going to get
combined. So by default, P4mer
e is bringing changes from bot
branches. But we can easily cha
ge this. So on the right sid
, we have two icons, purple and
green, and purple represents the
changes on the left side. So loo
at the legend over here, you
have a purple icon that rep
esents the left side, that cha
ges in the remote branch. The
green icon represents the cha
ges in the local branch, whi
h is master. So if we click on
he purple icon, now we only hav
the changes in the local bra
ch. Now while green is sel
cted, we can select the oth
r branch by holding down shi
t and clicking. So now we hav
the changes in both these bra
ches. This is the idea of P4mer
e or visual merge tools. Pretty
uch all merge tools out there w
rk in a similar fashion. If you
ave multiple conflicts in the
ame file, we can browse through
them using these buttons on the
oolbar. So we resolve the con
lict. When we are done. Just li
e before, we need to save th
changes and go back to the ter
inal and commit that. So we shou
d close P4merge Now back in the
erminal. Let's save the changes
and make a commit. I'm goin
to accept the default message.
So let's close that we know and
we've successfully mer
ed our branches.