So you'll learn that when doing
a merge, you may run into one or
more conflicts. Now what if
you're not quite ready to handle
these conflicts, perhaps we have
several conflicts and we're in
the middle of something. So we
don't have enough time to spend
on resolving this conflict. And
in situations like this, we can
easily go back to the state
before we started the merge. So
here we have a merge conflict.
to abort the merge. We simply
type Git merge, dash dash abort.
Now we're back to the state
before we started the merge. So
if we resolve some conflicts and
stage the changes, those
resolutions are gone. We're back
to a clean state before we start
at the me