Sometimes we do a merge, and
then find out that our code
doesn't get compiled, or our
application doesn't work. What
happens if you screw the merge
if we don't combine the changes
properly? In situations like
this, we need to undo the merge,
and then remerge. So let's have
a quick look at our history. On
the top, we have a merge commit,
let's say this is a faulty
merge. So we want to undo it,
you have two options. One option
is to remove this commit, as if
it was never there, I have to be
a bit careful with this
solution. Because as part of
removing this commit, we are
rewriting history, rewriting
history is totally fine if this
history is local in our
repository, but if you have
shared our commits with other
team members, if you have pushed
our commits to a remote
repository, then we should not
rewrite our history. We'll talk
about this in more detail in the
future. In situations like this,
instead of removing this commit,
we should revert it, which means
we're going to create a new
commit that will cancel all the
changes in this commit. In this
lesson, we're going to look at
both the solutions. First, let's
see how we can remove the last
commit. So here's a picture of
our history, both the head and
master pointers are pointing to
the last commit, which is a
merge commit. Now we're going to
use the reset command to move
both these pointers, and have
them point to the last commit on
the master branch before we
started the merge. Now look at
our merge commit. We don't have
any other comments or any
pointers pointing to this
commit. So from gits point of
view, this commit is garbage,
once in a while, get looks for
commits like this, and
automatically removes them from
our repository. So here in the
terminal, we type Git reset dash
dash heart, I will explain what
this means in a second, we will
reset head to head tilda one
that is one commit before the
last commit that what is this
hard option here. When resetting
the head pointer, we have three
options soft, mixed, and hard.
What is the difference? Well,
here we have our working
directory, our staging area, and
the last snapshot, let me reset
the head using the soft option.
Git is going to have the head
pointer point to a different
snapshot. But our staging area
and working directory are not
affected. If we use the mixed
option, which is the default
option. So we don't have to
specify it get is going to get
that new snapshot and put it in
the staging area as well. So if
you have local changes in our
working directory, they are not
affected, they're going to stay
there. If we use the hard
option, D is going to take that
new snapshot and put in our
working directory as well. So
all our environments are going
to look identical. This is the
state that we were in, before we
started the merge, all our
working environments were
identical. So back to the
terminal, we're going to reset
head to the last commit on the
master branch before we started
the merge, that is this commit
over here, update Change
Password. But before doing so, I
want to take a copy of the last
commit ID that is our merge
commit. Let's copy this and put
it somewhere. Now we type Git
reset dash dash hard head till
the one to go one step back.
Good. Now, head is pointing to
this commit over here, update
Change Password. Let's look at
our log. Look, the merge commit
is no longer in our history. But
it's still in our repository, so
we can recover it, I'm gonna
show you. So we type Git reset
dash dash heart, now we're going
to paste the ideal are merge
commit that we copied earlier.
Okay, let's go with that. Now
head is pointing to this commit
over here. That is our merge
commit. So let's look at our
history.
So here we have our merge
commit. Before that we have the
last commit on the bug fix
branch. And here's the last
commit on the master branch. So
you'll learn how to undo a merge
commit. But as I told you
before, you should do this only
if you haven't shared your
history with others. We'll talk
about that in the future. At
this stage, all these commits
are local in our repository. We
haven't shared our history with
others, we haven't pushed our
commits. So undoing is totally
fine. But if you have shared our
history, instead of ongoing, we
have to revert the last commit.
So we type Git revert head, we
want to revert the last commit,
which is our merge commit. Take
a look, we got this error saying
this commit is a merge, but no
dash m option was given what's
going on here. Here's our merge
commit. As you can see, a merge
commit has two parents, one
parent on the master branch, the
other on the feature branch. So
to revert this merge commit, we
have to tell git, how we want to
revert the changes. In this
case, we want to revert to this
commit over here on the last
commit on the master branch
before we started the merge.
This commit over here is the
first parent of our merge
commit, because our merge commit
is on the master branch. So the
first parent should also be on
the master branch. So we type
Git revert dash m one, which
means the first parent and then
we specified the target commit.
That is the last comment. Okay,
get open our default editor. So
here we have a default commit
message saying revert, and
here's the commit. We're
reverting down Below we have
more details. It's saying this
revert this commit over here
revising changes made to this
commit over here. We're going to
accept the default message so
close.
All right, we're done. Let's
look at our history.
So, here's our merge command.
Right after that we have a new
commit, which is reverting our
merge commit.