Here we have a bug fix branch
with two commits. B one and B
two. Let's say, we're done here.
So we do a merge. Now these
commits B one and B two are part
of the history of Master, right?
But what if these commits are
not good quality commits, maybe
they are too fine grained, or
they don't represent a single
logical chain set, maybe we have
mixed different things in each
commit. So these commits are not
good quality commits. Perhaps we
added this commit at checkpoints
along the way. So we don't
really care about the history of
the bug fix branch. So we don't
want these commits to pollute
the history of our master
branch. In situations like this,
we have a better solution called
squash merging. So let's undo
the merge. And we're going to
create a new commit that
combines all the changes in the
bug fix branch. So we have a
single logical chain set that
represents all the changes for
fixing this book. Now we can
apply this commit on top of
master. This is what we call
squash merging. Now, what you
need to pay attention to here is
that this new commit is not a
merge commit. Because it doesn't
have two parents, it doesn't
have a reference to be two, it's
just a regular commit that we
have added on top of master. Now
we're done with the bug fix
branch, so we can delete it. And
we are left with a simple clean
and linear history. This is the
benefit of squash merging. But
it doesn't mean you should use
this technique all the time, you
should use it with small, short
lived branches with bad history,
like bug fixes or features that
you can implement in a few hours
or in a day. Now let's see a
squash merging in action. So
let's start off by creating a
new branch called bug fix slash
photo upload. And this branch,
we're going to make two commits.
And in each commit, I'm going to
update one file. So let's
echobug fix to audience dot txt.
Now, we're going to commit using
dash a option, we're going to
stage and commit all the changes
in one step. We talked about
this at the beginning of the
course, remember, so let's give
it a message. Update audience.
txt. Now let's make a second
commit. So echo, bug fix to
Table of Contents. txt. Once
again, we're going to commit all
the changes in one step and say,
update table of contents. txt.
So here we have two commits.
Let's look at our history. So
git log, online, all graph. So
our bug fix branch is two
commits ahead of Master, the
first commit and the second
commit. In this case, we can do
a fast forward merge. But let's
say the master branch has
evolved. And we're not going to
do a fast forward merge. So
instead of doing a regular
merge, which adds a merge
commit, we're going to do a
squash merge. So first, we
switch to the master branch, git
switch master. Now in the past,
we typed Git merge, bug fix
slash photo upload, here, we're
going to add an option called
dash dash squash. Let's see what
happens. Get created a new
commit called a squash commit,
which combines the changes
across these two files. But we
don't have a commit yet. All th
se changes are in our staging ar
a, let me show you. So git st
tus, dash s. Look, both these fi
es are modified, and they're st
ged. So now we have to make a co
mit. So git commit dash m. he
e, we type a meaningful me
sage that represents all the ch
nges in our bug fix branch. So
we say, fix the bug on the ph
to upload page. Alright, le
's go. Let's bring up the hi
tory. So here on the master, we
have a new commit that co
bines all the changes for fi
ing this bug. So once we re
oved the bug fix branch, we
re going to end up with a si
ple, clean, linear history. Bu
before doing this, let me sh
w you something I'm currently on
master. Earlier, I showed you ho
to view the merged branches. We
type git branch, dash dash me
ged and look at our new br
nch. bug fix slash photo up
oad is not in this list, be
ause technically, we don't ha
e a merge commit that co
nects these two branches. So wh
n doing a squash merge, it's su
er important to remove your ta
get branch, otherwise, that br
nch will be sitting there, I ma
create confusion in the fu
ure. For example, you might ru
git branch, dash dash, no me
ge, and think you haven't me
ged this branch into master. Th
s is confusing. So we type gi
branch, dash D to remove bug fi
slash photo upload. Now we
re going to get an error. Can yo
tell why? Take a look at the br
nch photo upload is not fully me
ged. Because once again, git do
s not see this as a real me
ge. So here we have to en
orce the deletion using a ca
ital D. Okay, our branches go
e. Let's look at our history. On
more time.
So we have a simple linear
history, we have a single commit
that combines all the changes
for fixing the bug on the photo
upload page. One last thing
before we finish this lesson,
when are playing a squash merge
on top of Master, we might end
up with conflicts, the process
for resolving conflicts is
exactly like before. So we bring
up our mercial, resolve the
conflicts and then make a
commit.