Let's talk about another
technique for bringing changes
from one branch into another. So
here we have a feature branch
with two commits. When we're
done, we can do a merge. But
we'll end up with nonlinear
history. Now our history here is
not too bad, it's not really
complicated. But as we have more
branches, and we're working on
more complex scenarios, our
history might get really hard to
read. So here, we can use a
different technique, I will
result in linear history. So we
go back to the state. Before we
do a merge, look at the base of
our feature branch. This is
where we started the feature
branch right. Now using the
rebase command, we can change
the base of our feature branch,
so we can base it on the latest
commit on master. What's the
point of this? Well, look at the
shape of our history. We have a
direct linear path from feature
to master. So if you want to
merge the feature branch into
Master, we can do a fast forward
merge, and now we have linear
history. This is called
rebasing. Now, while it sounds
like a great idea, you need to
be cautious with rebasing
because rebasing rewrites
history, and that means you
should use rebasing only for
branches or commits that are
local in your repository. If you
have shared this commits with
other people in your team, if
you have pushed or changes, you
should not use rebasing.
Otherwise, you're going to make
a big mess. Let me explain why
rebasing rewrites history. So
here's the state before
rebasing, when you rebase, the
feature branch, Git is not going
to change the base or the parent
of f1, because commits and Git
are immutable, they cannot be
changed. So Git is going to look
at this commit is going to
create a new commit that looks
like f1 and f2, and apply them
on top of Master, then it's
going to move the feature
pointer over here. Now look at
f2, we don't have any branches
or any other commits pointing to
it. So at some point in the
future, Git is going to remove
this commit. So we are
ssentially rewriting history,
hese two commits that we have
ere, they're not the same
ommit as before. So if you have
hared f one and F two with
thers, and other people have
reated a new commit on top of
2. Now, after rebasing, their
istory is going to get screwed.
o let's create a new feature
ranch called shopping cart, git
witch dicey feature slash
hopping cart. Now let's make a
ommit and this branch. So I'm
oing to echo hello to cart, the
xt, the change doesn't really
atter. Now, let's add this to
he staging area, and then make
commit. Here, we'll say add
art, a txt. Now let's look at
ur history. So our shopping
art branch is one commit ahead
f Master, right. So if we do a
erge, git will do a Fast
orward march. Now let's go back
o the master branch and make a
ew commit. With this, our
ranches are going to divert. So
e should either do a three way
erge or rebase. So let's go
ack to master. Here, we're
oing to echo hello to Table of
ontents. txt. Now we're going
o commit the changes and say
pdate table of contents. Good.
et's pull up the history one
ore time. Look, our branches
ave diverged. This is the base
f this branches. This is where
e created the shopping cart
ranch. Now in our shopping cart
ranch, we have this comment
ver here. And in Master, we
ave another commit. So our
ranches have diverged. Now the
umber of commits doesn't
atter, we could have 10s of
ommits in each of these
ranches. What we want to do now
s rebase, the shopping cart
ranch. So we want to change its
ase from this commit over here
o the last commit on master. So
irst, we have to switch to our
arget branch, git switch,
eature slash shopping cart. Now
e're going to run git rebase.
aster, we're telling get to
hange the base of this branch
o the last commit on master.
eautiful. In this case,
ebasing was done successfully.
hat is not the case in the real
orld. Most of the time, when
ou rebase, you end up with
onflicts. We'll talk about it
n a moment. But first, let's
ull up our history one more
ime. So git log, alright, look,
ur branches have no longer
iverse, we have a direct linear
ath from our feature branch,
nto master. So now if we decide
o do a merge, git will do a
ast forward merge to bring the
aster pointer upward. So let's
witch to master and we run git
erge feature slash shopping
art. Look, we have a fast
orward match. Now let's pull up
he history one more time.
So both our branches are
pointing to the same commit over
here, and we have a simple,
clean, linear history. Now what
if there's a conflict? Well,
let's have a look. So currently,
we're on master. That's Aiko,
ocean, to table of content, that
txt, that change doesn't matter.
I just want to create a conflict
and change Now, let's commit the
change and say update table of
content. txt. Go ahead. Now
let's switch to our feature
branch and make a conflict and
change. So we're going to write
something else to Table of
Contents. txt. So Git switch,
feature slash shopping cart. Now
we Echo, let's say, mountain to
table of content dot txt, and
then make a commit, right
mountain to table of content.
Now our branches have diverged,
and we have a conflicting
change. Let's verify this. So
git log, look, our branches have
diverged one more time, we have
this commit in our shopping cart
branch, and this other commit in
master. And here's the base of
our feature branch. So when we
try to rebase it on top of this
commit, we're going to see a
conflict, take a look. So we go
to our feature branch, and then
run git rebase. Master. Look, we
have a conflict and this file
table of contents. txt. So here,
we should resolve the conflict.
Exactly like before, we're going
to launch our merge tool, so we
say Git merge tool. So here, we
need to decide how we're going
to combine the changes. For this
demo, it doesn't really matter,
I'm going to pick one of those
changes. Now we save the
changes, and close the format.
So as you can see, in the
terminal window, we are in the
middle of rebasing, our shopping
cart branch. So next, we type
Git rebase dash dash continue to
tell Git to apply the next
commit on top of master. If the
next commit also has a conflict,
again, we're going to end up
with the same state. So we have
to resolve the conflict and then
tell Git to continue rebasing.
Alternatively, we can use
another option to skip, this
will skip the current commit,
and move on to the next commit.
So if we look at the conflict,
and we realized that we don't
actually care about this commit,
we can skip it. We have another
option here, and that is abort.
This is useful in situations
where we have so many commits to
apply on top of Master, perhaps
our branches have diverged for a
long time. In that case, if we
don't have enough time for
resolving all these conflicts
and going through a complete
rebase we can afford the rebase
here. So this will take us back
to the previous state before we
started rebasing. One last thing
before we finish this lesson,
look at this question mark over
here. That means we have new
untracked files. Let's verify so
get status. Look. You have table
of content dot txt, that origin
What is this? Well, our merge
tool in this case p for merge
automatically created this file
as a backup. So let's look at
the content of this file. So
this is our table of content
file. Before we resolve the
conflict, we don't want this
file in our repository. So we
can remove it using the rm
command or get clean, assuming
that we don't have other
untracked files that we want to
add to our repository. Now our
working directory is clean. We
don't have any new untracked
files, but for the future to
prevent our merge tool from
automatically generating thes
files. We can set Git config
dash dash global merge tool do
keep backup to fals