So you'll learn how to cherry
pick a particular commit from
another branch and apply it to
the current branch. But what if
you're only interested in a
single file, not a whole commit,
let me show you how to bring a
given file from another branch
into the current branch. So for
this demo, I'm going to create
another branch called feature
slash send email. That is
scratch, I'm going to make a
change to our table of content
file. So echo, river to table of
content dot txt. Now, let's make
a comment, and say update table
of content. Now let's say we
want to bring this table of
content file to our master
branch. So first, we switch to
master. Now we're going to use
the Restore command. You'll
learn about this earlier in the
course. So we type Git restore,
dash di source, or we could use
dash s for short. We set this to
our target branch, feature slash
send email. And then we specify
our file name. In this case,
table of contents. txt, the
earlier I told you that
sometimes get cannot interpret
the file name. So in those
situations, we have to add
double hyphens here to separate
the options from the file or the
files here. Now when I run this
command, Git is going to restore
our table of content file in our
working directory. From the
latest version of this file
stored in this branch. Take a
look. So our working directory
is dirty. Let's get a short
status. So we have some local
changes in this file, we can
view the contents of this file
using the cat command. So cat
table of content, that txt. So
this is the change that we
applied in our feature branch.
Now we can stage the change and
committed in the current branch.