Let's see how we can work with
branches in VS code. As I told
you in the previous section, we
VS code has limited good
features. So to bring additional
features, we have to install an
extension called git lens. If
ou missed that video in the
revious section, go to the
xtensions panel and search for
uidelines. This is the
xtension we're going to use to
ork with branches. So once you
nstall this, you're going to
ee this new icon over here.
ere's our Venus repository.
ver here we have this folder
alled branches, we can see all
f our branches here. So master
s our current branch, as
ndicated by this tick icon.
We also have these folders, bug
fix,
and feature. And the reason we
have these folders is because I
used a forward slash in naming
this branches. So bug fix slash,
whatever. That is the benefit of
using this convention. Here, we
can change the layout. So
instead of a tree structure, we
can view our branches in a list.
So we click on this icon, all of
our branches are listed here.
And in front of each branch, we
can see the last time this
branch was updated. So as a best
practice, if you're done with a
branch, make sure to delete it.
Otherwise, all these branches
hanging there, it's just going
to create confusion for you. Now
we can expand any of these
branches to look at its history.
Unfortunately, at the time of
recording this lesson, we cannot
see all of our branches in the
graph. To do that, we're going
to use another extension, which
I'm going to talk about at the
end of this lesson.
So master is the current branch.
Now I'm going to create a new
branch based on the last commit
on master. So we right click
here. And here we have a few
options, we can switch to this
branch, whichever and in this
branch, create a new branch and
create attack.
So let's create a new branch.
I'm going
to call this feature slash reset
that password. Now we get this
error saying this is not a valid
branch name. I don't know what
this is coming up, don't worry
about it, just press enter. Here
we have a few options, we can
create this branch, or we can
create this branch and switch to
it. Or we can cancel, I'm going
to go with the second option.
Good. So we're currently on our
feature branch, we can also see
the current branch over here in
the status bar. Now let's make a
new commit in this branch. So
I'm going to Open Table of
Contents. txt
and say, beautiful weather,
save the changes. Now we go to
the source control panel,
unfortunately, we got is not
picking up our change.
So we have to
refresh the view.
Good. So here's the change.
Let's give this committee a
message, we can say, right,
beautiful weather to table of
content.
Now, we make a comment. Good. So
let's go to git lens.
Here in our branches,
we can see this new commit over
here.
Now after a while, as we make
new commits, we want to compare
this branch with Master to see
how these branches have
diverged. So with our feature
branch selected, here, we can
click on compare. And in this
drop down list, we can see all
of our branches. So I'm going to
select master. To see how this
branch is different from Master.
Let's expand this folder. So
currently we have one commit.
And this commit is in our
feature branch. in a real
situation, we could have several
commits here. Some of these
commits are on Master, the
others are on the feature
branch, we can also see the
summary of files that are
changed. So in this example, our
table of content file has
changed, we can click on it
to see the exact lines of code
that have changed. In this case,
we have this new line in our
feature branch. So after
immerses branch into Master,
this new line is going to be
added to table of content in
master. Now I want to go back to
master and make a conflicting
change. So we can click on this
branch on the status bar and go
to master wellness Open Table of
Contents. And read something
else here like sunny day, save
the changes. Now if we go to
source control panel, once
again, we have to refresh the
view. I don't know what's going
on here, let's say write,
Sunday, the table of contents.
So you haven't you come in here
and now we want to do a merge.
So we get to git lens. We're
urrently on master.
Now want to merge our feature
branch into master.
So we right click on our branch
and select merge branch into
current which is Master, we can
also do a rebase. Either way,
we're going to end up with a
conflict.
In this demo, I'm going to go
with merge branch.
Here we have a few options, we
can just do a default merge. So
that is equivalent to executing
Git merge target branch. We have
another option here. Fast
forward merge. So look at this
option dash f f dash only with
this, we're telling it Hey, to
merge only fast forward is
possible. Otherwise don't do a
merge. We have another option
here. No Fast Forward merge. We
talked about This earlier in
this section, if you select
this, it is going to create a
merge commit, even if fast
forward is an option, you also
have squash merge. Now in this
demo, I'm going to go with the
default patch. So look in the
terminal window, you got a
conflict, a conflict in our
table of content file. So on the
left,
we go to our source control
panel.
Let's refresh the view one more
time.
So under merge changes, we can
see all conflicted files. So
here we have a C, which means
conflict. If you open this, we
can see the conflict markers. So
we can manually edit this file
or use one of these options over
here. In this case, I'm going to
accept those changes and save.
Now, we need to commit the
changes. So first, we need to
stage them. So we click on this
icon.
Now this file is in the staging
area.
And here we have the default
commit message. Well,
let's make a commit. Good.
So I can get Lance.
Here's our master branch. And
here's our merge commit. Now,
let's say we screwed something
up, we have a faulty merge, so
we cannot compile our code, or
application doesn't work, you
want to undo this merge. What
should we do here? Well, let's
read click this, we can revert
this commit. So it's gonna
create a new commit that will
undo the changes in this commit.
Unfortunately, at the time of
recording this, this option
doesn't work. So if you select
this, and go ahead with
reverting this commit, and we
get this error in the terminal
saying, dash m option was not
given. We talked about this
earlier in the section. So
because a merge commit has two
parents, and we have to specify
the parent number in order to
revert this commit. So for this
demo, I'm going to undo our
merge commit. So back in Git
lens, here's our merge commit,
e want to reset the head to the
revious commit over here. So if
e right click on this and
elect
reset to commit,
here we have a few options, we
can do a soft reset or hard
reset. A soft reset only updates
the head pointer. But a hard
reset also updates the staging
area and the working directory
to match the snapshot pointed to
the latest commit. So here we're
going to go with hard reset.
Good. Now our merge commit is
gone.
here and git lens, we also h
ve
our stashes. Currently, we don't
have any stashes.
So I can go to our table of
content file and make some
changes. Now over here, we can
stash all the local changes. So
let's select that. Here we
supply a message and let's say
new tax rolls, enter. So we have
a new stash. Here we can see a
summary of the changes. So we
have zero new files, one
modified file and zero deleted
files. That some point in the
future, we're going to apply
this stash to our working
directory. So we can click on
this icon, apply a stash. Here
we have a few options, we can
apply to stash, or we can pop
this stash. This is going to
apply this stash and then drop
it or we can cancel. So I'm
going to apply the stash. Okay,
our changes are back. And we can
still see the stash here. When
we were done,
we can delete it very easily.
So these are some of the
features we have in kidlat. I
told you that good lens doesn't
provide a graph of our branches.
To see a graph, we should
install an extension called get
graph.
So here in the extensions panel,
get graph.
It's right here.
This gives us a beautiful graph
of our branches. So once you
install this
here in the source control
panel,
you're going to see a new icon
called get graph.
And now we can clearly see a
graph of our branches. For
example, here we have this
branch feature reset password
that is not merge into master.
So we have this commit that is
not included in master down
below. You can see earlier we
created this branch and then
later we merge it into master