So what is branching all about?
Well, branching allows us to
diverge from the main line of
work and work on something else
in isolation. Conceptually, you
can think of a branch like a
separate, isolated workspace. So
we have our main workspace,
which is called Master, we can
have another workspace, we're
working on a new feature in
isolation. While we're
developing this new feature, our
code may get unstable. So we
don't want to release the code
in this workspace. We continue
working here, when we're done,
we test our code. And after we
fix all the bugs, then we bring
the changes in this workspace
into the master. This is called
merging. So branching allows us
to work on different work items.
without messing up with the main
line of work, we keep the main
line as stable as possible, so
we can release it anytime. Also,
anyone joining our team can
start off on a stable codebase.
That's the idea of branching.
Now, the way git manages
branches is very different from
many other version control
systems like subversion. In
subversion, when we create a new
branch, subversion takes a copy
of our entire working directory
and stores it somewhere else.
What if you have hundreds or
thousands of files in our
project, all these files have to
be copied. And this operation
can take a little while. That's
why a lot of subversion users
hate branching, because it's
slow and can waste a lot of disk
space. Git branches are super
fast and cheap, because a branch
and Git is just a pointer to a
commit. So the master branch is
just a pointer to the last
commit in the main line of work.
As we make new commits, get most
this pointer forward
automatically. So it knows what
is the latest code in the main
line of work. That is the
snapshot stores in this commit.
When we create a new branch, git
creates a new pointer that can
be moved around. This pointer is
just a tiny file that contains a
40 byte commit ID. That's why
creating a branch in Git is
blazingly fast. Now when we
switch to this branch and make
new commits get most of this
point forward, the master
pointer stays where it is, so
git knows the latest code in
each branch. Let me switch back
to master. It takes the snapshot
from the commit that master
points to and resets our working
directory to that snapshot. So
we always have a single working
directory. Now how does git know
which branch we're currently
working on using a special
pointer called head. This coiner
is also another type of file
that contains the name of a
branch like master. Let me
switch to a different branch.
Git moves the head pointer out.
o it updates a tiny file and
rites the name of the target
ranch. This is how we can track
hat branch we're currently
orking on. And throughout the
ection. You're gonna learn
verything you need to know to
ork with branches.