Let's see how we can work with
branches and GitKraken. So as yo
can see, here, we have a be
utiful graph of our branches. An
we can easily see all the br
nches we have created and wh
ther these branches have been me
ged into master or not. For ex
mple, this feature branch, re
et password has a single co
mit, and it hasn't been me
ged into master. In contrast, we
have this other branch here, bu
fix slash Change Password. Ea
lier, we created this branch fr
m this commit on Master, we ad
ed one commit to this branch, an
then merge it into master. So
here's our merge commit. Now le
's create a new branch from Ma
ter. So master is the current br
nch, we can also change the cu
rent branch from this drop do
n list over here. Now, we ri
ht click here, and go to cr
ate branch here. Let's give it
a name, like feature slash de
ete user. So now we are on th
s new branch, we can right cl
ck it and rename or deleted. No
let's go to VS code, make so
e changes and add a commit to th
s branch. So in our table of co
tent file, I'm going to add tw
lines, green tea save, GitKrak
n has detected our change
. So let's look at them. Here's
the file that we have modifi
d, let's state the change
and make a comment. We can sa
update table of content. Good.
o our branch pointer move forwar
. Now we have one extra commit
here that is not in master
Next, I'm going to switch
back to master and make a confli
ting change. So double click
aster. Here in table of conten
, I'm going to say black tea. O
ay. GitKraken has detected
ur change. So let's go ahead and
make another commit. Good. So
ook, our branches have diverged.
Master is here, our feature b
anches over here, and we can se
the divergence. Now before do
ng a merge, let's compare t
ese branches. So currently
the last commit on our featu
e branch is selected, I'm going
to hold down the Shift and selec
the master branch. Now the t
ps of these branches have been
selected. So we can see their
diff over here, the only file
that has been changed across th
se two branches is our table of
ontent file. So take a look. Obv
ously, we have a conflict
nd change on line three. So
when we do a merge, we're goi
g to run into conflict.
Now let's close this. And to em
rge. So master is the current b
anch, we right click on our fe
ture branch. and here we can do
a rebase or a merge. Let's go
ith merge, our merge failed. A
d on the right side, we can se
merge conflicts detected.
so here we can see all the confl
ct files. Let's select table of
ontent, I love this merge too
built into GitKraken. So
on the left side, we have chan
es on master. And on the right
side, we have changes on o
r feature branch. Now down bel
w, we can see the output. So w
can go ahead and select the c
anges in Master, followed by
hanges in our feature bran
h. If this is not what we want
we can always deselect one
or more of these lines, or ch
nge the order. If you have mor
than one conflict, we can brows
through them over here. Very s
mple. When we're done, we cli
k Save. Our table of content f
le is now staged. And here's t
e default commit message merg
branch feature slash delete
user. Here we can abort the ma
riage or committed. Let's go ahe
d with that. So here's our m
rge commit beautiful. N
w let's say we screwed some
hing up. So we're going to und
this merge, we can either rever
it, or reset the head to the
revious commit. So with this co
mit selected, we can right cl
ck and go to revert commit, GitK
aken and saying Do you want to
mmediately commit the reve
ted changes? Yes. So here's
he revert of our merge commit. A
ternatively, we can reset the h
ad to the commit before our merg
commit. So here's our merg
commit. And here's the last
commit on master. We can
ight click this commit and go t
reset master to this commit. He
e we have three options you hav
seen before. Soft, mixed and
hard. We're gonna go with h
rd. Good so our merge commit is
now gone. So this was the es
ence of working with branches a
d GitKraken. As you can see, Gi
Kraken it makes it incredibly e
sy to manage branches and r
solve conflicts.