Let's say we just got a bug
report. Now to fix this bug,
first, we should create a new
branch called bug fix. So we
type git branch bug fix. Now to
see the list of branches, we
type git branch. So currently,
we have two branches, bug fix,
and master. There is an asterisk
before Master, which means we're
currently on the master branch.
You can also see that over here,
as I told you earlier in the
course, this is coming from Zed
sh, or Z shell with Git plugin.
So if you're on Mac, to see
something like this, you should
install set sh with Git plugin.
If you're on Windows, you should
install posh Git. This is really
helpful because here we can
clearly see what is the current
branch. One of the issues that a
lot of people face is they
accidentally commit their code
to the wrong branch. So we're
currently on the master branch.
There's another way to know the
current branch, we can type git
status on branch master. Now, to
fix this imaginary bug. First,
we have to change the current
branch to bug fix. There are two
ways to do this. In the past, we
used the checkout command. But
this command had multiple
applications, a lot of people
found it confusing. So these
days, we have a new command for
switching branches. So get
switch, bug fix. Now here on the
bug fix branch beautiful. But
before going forward, I want to
rename this branch, it's not
clear what bug we're trying to
fix here. And also in the
future, it's very likely that
we're going to have 10s or
hundreds of other bugs to fix.
So it's better to use a more
specific name. To rename this
branch, we can type git branch
dash m, we type the old name,
and then the new name, we can
use a convention like bug fix
slash signup form, assuming that
this bug is in our signup form.
If you don't like it forward
slash, you can use a hyphen
here. That's a matter of
personal preference. Okay, now
we can see our branches renamed
beautiful. So to make some
changes, let's open audience dot
txt in VS code or your favorite
code editor. Right here, I'm
going to make a few changes.
First, I'm going to rename
audience to who this course is
for and then I'm going to add a
border. And finally, I'm going
to remove the slide. So we have
three kinds of changes here.
addition, modification, and
deletion. Okay? Obviously, these
changes have nothing to do with
fixing a bug on a signup form.
But here, we're not working on
an application. So don't worry
about the differences. I'm just
teaching you how to use various
tools and get the name of our
branches, the changes we'll make
and the commit messages don't
matter. Now save the changes.
Back in the terminal. Our
working directory is dirty, as
we can see from the yellow
marker. So as from status, we
can clearly see that you've
modified this file and this file
is not staged. So let's add it
to the staging area. And then
committed, we can say fix the
bug that prevented the users
from signing up.
Good. Now let's look at our log.
So git log, one line, see what's
going on here. On the top, we
have head pointing to the bug
fix branch. That means we're
currently on the bug fix branch.
And here's the latest commit and
the bug fix branch. Now below
that, we can see our master
branch, which is just a pointer
to a commit. So as we can see,
our master branch is one commit
behind the bug fix branch. At
some point in the future, we're
going to merge the bug fix
branch with the master branch to
bring the master branch up. But
don't worry about it. Now, let's
just focus on managing branches.
So in audience dot txt, we made
a few changes. And these changes
are only visible in the book fix
scratch. So if we switch back to
the master branch, and open
audience dot txt, we see the old
version of this file. So
branches allow us to work on
different tasks in isolation,
the code we have in these
branches are isolated, at some
point, we will merge them to
bring them together. Now while
we're on the master branch, if
we look at our log, on the top,
we can see head is pointing to
the master branch. But we don't
see the bug fix branch, because
bug fix is ahead of the master
branch. So its commits are not
listed here by default. To view
the commits across all branches,
we use the all option. Now, even
though we are on the master
branch, we can see the commits
in other branches, in this case,
the bug fix branch. Now at some
point in the future, when we are
done with the bug fix branch,
when we merge it into the master
branch, we need to delete it. So
we type git branch dash D, bug
fix slash sign up for the here
we get an error saying the
branch bug fix is not fully
merged. You're seeing this error
because we have some changes in
the bug fix branch that are not
merged with a master branch. So
by default, it prevents us from
accidentally deleting the sprach
unless we merge it first. But if
you're pretty sure that we don't
want the changes in this branch,
we can force the deletion by
using a capital So we say git
branch dash, capital D. In this
video, I'm not going to delete
this branch because later in the
section, we're going to merge
the changes in this branch with
Master