As we commit to our branches, we
need to know how they're
diverging from master. So in
this video, I'm going to show
you a couple of different ways
to compare branches. So
currently we are on master. At
some point in the future, we're
going to merge the bug fix
branch into master. But before
doing so, you want to know what
commits are coming in master. So
we type git log Master, colon,
colon, bug fix slash signup
form. So this means show me all
the commits that are in bug fix
branch, and are not in master.
Currently, we have only a single
commit, if you had more commits,
all of them would be listed
here. And just like before, we
can use the one line option to
make the output more concise.
Now, what if you want to see the
actual changes and not the list
of commits? Well, what tool do
we use for seeing the changes?
diff. So git diff, we're going
to compare master with the bug
fix scratch. So we type master
colon colon bug fix slash signup
form. So now we know that once
we merge the bug fix branch into
master in audience dot txt,
e're going to have these
hanges. So these two lines are
oing to get removed and
eplaced with these two lines.
here's a shorter way to write
his command. Because we're
urrently on Master, we don't
ave to type master dot dot
ere. So we can type get def bug
ix slash sign up for. So this
hows the differences between
his branch and the current
ranch, which is master. Now
ometimes, we don't want to see
he changes in terms of the
ode. We just want to know what
iles are going to be affected.
n those cases, we can use one
f the options we talked about
n the previous section, name
nly, or name status. So once we
erge the bug fix branch into
aster audience, that txt is
oing to be modified.