So as I told you before, when we
switch branches, git resets our
working directory to the
snapshot stored in the last
commit of the target branch.
Now, if you have local changes
in our working directory that we
haven't committed yet, these
changes could get lost in these
situations. It doesn't allow us
to switch branches. Let me show
you how this happens and what
you should do about it. So in
the previous lesson, we made
some changes in audience that
txt in our bug fix branch, that
currently we're on the master
branch. So let's open audience.
txt and make some other kind of
changes. So here I'm going to
add an asterisk just to indicate
a change, save back in the
terminal, our working directory
is dirty, because we have some
local changes we haven't
committed yet. So let's say
we're in the middle of
something, and then we have to
quickly switch to the bug fix
branch. If we type Git switch,
bug fix signup form, we get an
error saying your local changes
to the following files would be
overwritten by Checkout, please
commit your changes, or stash
them before you switch branches.
Now, in this case, I don't want
to commit the changes, because
I'm not done yet. So in
situations like this, we should
stash our changes, slashing
something means storing it in a
safe place. So we're going to
store this somewhere in our Git
repository. But this is not
going to be part of our history.
Let me show you how this works.
So we type Git stash, push dash
m, and give it a message. With
this message, we can tell what
these changes are all about.
That's a new tax rules. So I was
working on the new tax rules.
And then I had to quickly switch
to the bug fix scratch, right.
So save working directory and
index date on master. And here's
the message. Now as you can see,
over here, we have one stash.
Just remember why default, new
ontrack files are not included
in your stash. So as an example,
if I create a new file here,
let's echo hello to new file.
txt. Now let's run a short
status. So we have a new file.
If I stash the changes, this new
untracked file is not going to
be included in the stash by
default. To include it, we have
to use the all option. So we say
Git stash, push dash dash all or
just dash a and then dash m. or
we can combine these two
options. Interesting option. Now
we'll give you the message, my
new stash. Of course, the
message should be something more
meaningful. So now we have two
slashes. You can see that over
here. To view our stashes with
tap get stash list. So you have
two slashes. Each stash has a
unique identifier stash add. In
curly braces, we have an index.
Now as you can see, our working
directory is clean. So we can
switch to the bug fix branch. No
problem, we can do our work
here. When we are done, we get
back to the master. At this
point, we want to apply the
changes from one of our stashes
to our working directory. But
before doing so, we want to look
at those changes to see what
lines of code have been
modified. So we type Git stash
show. And here we type the name
of the stash like stash at curly
braces one. Now we can make this
shorter by using just the
sequence number. Now we know
that in stash number one, one
file has been changed. That is
audience dot txt. Here we have
two changes, one insertion and
one deletion. So we can go ahead
and apply this stash on our
working directory. So Git stash
apply once the changes are
applied to our working directory
beautiful. Now when we're done
with this stash, we want to
remove it to clean things up. So
we can type Git stash drop one,
that stash is removed. Let's
look at our stash the small more
time. We have one more stash.
Let's say we don't need this
anymore. So we can type Git
stash drops zero or to remove
all stashes we can type Git
stash clear. All our stashes are
gone.