Merging is all about bringing
changes from one branch to
another. In git, we have two
types of merges, fast forward
merges and three way merges.
Let's look at each of these
merges using a real example. So
here's the master branch with
three commits. And we create a
new branch called bug fix, as I
told you before, and get a
branch is just a pointer to a
commit. So in this case, both
master and bug fix pointers are
pointing to the same commit. Now
we'll switch to the bug fix
branch and make a couple of
commits. And we're done here.
And now we need to bring the
changes back to master. Now,
because these branches have not
diverged, and there is a direct
linear path from bug fix to
master, all good has to do to
merge the changes is to bring
the master pointer forward. This
is what we call a fast forward
merge. If you're confused about
this, let me give you a simple
example. So forget about gift
for a second. Imagine we have a
directory called master. And the
code in this directory is at
version 1.0. We take a copy of
this directory and call it bug
fix. At this point in time, the
code in this directory is are
identical, right? Now we start
making some changes to the bug
fix directory. So we get to
version 1.2. We're done here. We
want to bring the changes back
to master. How do we do this?
Well, one way is to copy all the
files from bug fix into master.
But this is not the best way to
solve this problem. What if you
have thousands of files, this
copy operation might take a few
seconds, there is a better way,
since we don't have any
additional changes in master.
And essentially what we have in
master is the first version of
bug fix, we can simply rename
bug fix to master. So from this
point forward, we can say this
is our new master directory died
of a fast forward merge and Git
is very similar. So if two
branches have not diverged, and
there is a direct linear path
from the target branch to the
source branch, git runs a fast
forward merge, it simply brings
the pointer of the source branch
forward. Now that we're done
with the bug fix branch, we can
simply remove it, which removes
the pointer. Now let's look at
an example of a three way
merge. In this example, our bu
fix branch is two commits ah
ad of master. But before we me
ge it with Master, let's go ba
k to master and add an ad
itional commit. Now our br
nches are diverged. So we ha
e some changes in master that do
't exist in the bug fix sc
atch. So if you run a merge, gi
cannot move the master po
nter forward and have it po
nt to the same commit as bug fi
, because otherwise we'll lo
e the latest commit in the ma
ter branch. So when we run a me
ge, git creates a new commit th
t combines the changes from th
se two branches. The reason th
s is called a three way merge is
because this new commit is ba
ed on three different commits th
common ancestor of our br
nches, which includes the be
ore code, and the tips of our br
nches, which contains the af
er code. So Git looks at th
ee different snapshots, the be
ore snapshot, and after sn
pshots and based on these, it wi
l figure out how we should co
bine the changes. So we cr
ate this new commit, which is ca
led a merge commit. So to re
ap, in Git we have two types of
merges. Fast forward merges, wh
ch happen if branches have no
diverse and three way me
ges, which happen if branches ha
e diverged. Over the next few vi
eos, we're going to see ex
mples of these merges in ac
ion.