Let's see a real example of a
fast forward merge. So first,
let's look at our log. And by
the way, when you're using
branches, it's a good idea to
always include the graph option.
At this point in time, you're
not going to see any
differences. But as we go
forward, you will see that the
graph option will give us a
better representation of our
branches and how they diverged.
And, of course, I know this
command is very long, and you're
not supposed to write this every
single time. That's why we use
aliases. But as I told you
before, in this course, I'm not
going to use aliases, because I
want anyone to be able to follow
this course. So let's look at
our log. As you can see, our bug
fix branch is one commit ahead
of master. Also, as you can see,
here, we have a linear path. So
if you start from bug fix, we
can get to master. So master has
not diverged from bug fix. That
means when we run a merge, git
will fast forward Master, let me
show you. So to bring the
changes from the bug fix crash
into Master, first, we should be
on master and then run git
merge, bug, fix slash, sign up
for him, I don't know why my
autocomplete is not working on
this machine. So let's run.
Look, we have a fast forward
merge. And this file is the only
file that was changed with five
changes. Now, let's look at our
history one more time. So now
both these branches are pointing
to the same commit, which is the
latest commit over here, and we
have a linear history. Now it is
possible to disable a fast
forward merge. And this has a
number of benefits. So let's
create a new bug fix branch,
make a new commit to it, and
then merge it with Master using
a no Fast Forward option. So
earlier, I told you that to
create a branch we type git
branch, and then type the branch
name. But after this, we have to
switch to that branch. So there
are two steps we have to follow.
Now let me show you a shortcut.
We can type Git switch, dash c
for create. And with this, we
can create and switch to a
branch in one step. So I'm going
to call this branch bug fixed
slash login for now we are on
this new branch. So let's open
our table of contents file and
add an asterisk here, save back
to the terminal, let's commit
the changes. For the commit
message, I'm going to say update
table of contents. txt. Okay,
now let's look at our history.
So git log, one nine, all graph,
take a look. So our new branch
is one commit ahead of master.
And by the way, we probably
don't need this branch anymore,
so we can drop it. But that
aside, let's merge our new
branch into master using a no
Fast Forward option. So first,
we have to switch to a master,
get switch master. Now we run
git merge, here, we have to use
the no Fast Forward option. So
no, fast forward, then we type
the branch name. So bug fix
slash login form. So we this
pretending good, hey, even if
fast forward is possible, don't
do it, create a merge commit
that combines all the changes in
this target branch and bring
them into Master, take a look.
So our default editor is opened.
Here, we have to type a commit
message because we're going to
have a merge commit and new
commit in the master branch, by
default, gets suggest this
message, merge branch, bug, fix
slash login form into Master,
most of the time, the default
message is totally fine. So we
can close this.
Go back to the terminal, we no
longer have a fast forward
merge. So let's look at our
history one more time, using the
graph option. Let's see what's
going on here. So here's our new
bug fix branch, which originated
from this commit over here. So
before we merge this into Master
Master was pointing to this
commit. And this is when we
created our new bug fix scratch.
And this branch, we added a new
commit, which was for updating
our table of content file, then
we merge this branch into
master. So see the graph, this
is coming from the graph option.
If we don't use the graph
option, we'll see everything in
a linear way. So our master is
pointing to this commit, which
is our merge commit. And here's
the commit message that you just
saw. Now, what is the benefits
of this approach? Why should we
disable Fast Forward marriages?
Well, this is one of those areas
that gets a bit controversial.
And they get committed to we
have two groups of people. Some
people hate merge commits, and
they argue that these merge
commits pollute the history,
they make it harder to read and
understand what's going on,
especially as we have more and
more branches. These people
prefer a linear history. On the
other hand, we have another
group of people who argue that
these merge commits are a true
reflection of history, a true
reflection of what actually
happened when we merged our
branches and how they were
merged. In my opinion, both his
arguments are valid. It's
definitely easier to read a
linear history, but you should
also remember that a linear
history is not your true
history. It's like now that
aside, these merge commits have
another benefit, they make it
easier for us to undo a feature.
Let's talk about it using a real
example. So here we have two
branches master and feature. And
our branches have not diverse.
So there is a direct linear path
from feature to master. Right.
So here, we can use a fast
forward merge. But let's see
what happens. If you don't use a
fast forward merge, you're gonna
have a merge commit, that
combines all the changes in the
feature branch. So if you have f
one and F two in the feature
branch, this new merge commit
combines all the changes in F
one and F two. Now, let's see,
we work on this feature. And
then next day, we are told to
remove this feature from the
codebase, we can easily revert
the last commit in the master
branch. We'll talk about
reverting commits in the future
when we talk about rewriting
history. But basically, by
reverting a commit, we create a
new commit, that is the opposite
of that commit. So essentially,
it undoes everything that has
happened in another commit. So
if we use a merge commit, there
is a single commit that we have
to revert. In contrast, if we
use the Fast Forward option, our
master pointer is going to move
over here. And now if you want
to take out this feature from
the codebase, we have more
commits that we have to revert,
and this can get a bit more
complex. So once again, both his
arguments are valid, it really
depends on your team culture and
the kind of project you're
working on. So I leave it up to
you to decide what approach
works best for you. Now, where
you work, you might have a
policy in your company is saying
no Fast Forward merges. In that
case, you don't want to type Git
merge, no Fast Forward every
time What if you forget, so let
me show you a better way. We can
disable Fast Forward measures
for a particular repository or
for all of our repositories. So
we type Git config. Fast
forward, no, this will disable
Fast Forward only in the current
repository. But if you want this
to apply to all of your
repositories, of course, you
should use the global option
here.