Now let's look at an example of
a three way merge. First, let's
look at our history. So this is
where we are, our master branch
is at this commit, which is a
merge commit. Now I'm going to
create a new branch for
implementing a new feature. So
get switch, dash C for create,
we're going to call that branch
feature slash, Change Password.
So now we have this new branch.
Let's look at our history one
more time. So at this point,
both these pointers are Change
Password pointer and master
pointer are pointing to the same
commit. Now, what you want to
explore in this lesson is how
two branches can diverge. So
we're currently on the Change
Password branch. Let's make a
commit here, I'm going to echo
hello to, let's say change as
password to txt. Now we're going
to save the changes and commit
them and say, build the Change
Password form.
Now, let's look at our history
again.
So as you can see, our Change
Password branch is one commit
ahead of the master branch,
right? But our branches have not
diverged yet, because there is a
direct linear path from the
Change Password branch to
master. So to make this branches
diverged, I'm going to go back
to master and make a new commit.
So Git switch Master, let's open
objectives dot txt, and make a
small change here, it doesn't
really matter. Now, back into
terminal, let's run git add, and
then commit and say, update
objectives. txt. So now both the
master and Change Password
branches have a new commit, take
a look. So git log. Okay, here's
master. And here's the Change
Password branch. As we can see,
our branches have diverged. And
this is the commit where we
started the Change Password
branch, we added a new commit in
this branch and got back to
master and added a new commit to
master. Now we do not have a
direct linear path from change
password to master. So if we
start from here, we cannot go to
master. So when we try to merge
the changes, Git is going to run
a three way merge, it's going to
look at the tips of this
branches, which is this commit.
And this commit over here, is
going to compare these with our
common ancestor, which is in
this case, this commit over
here, based on the differences,
it's going to figure out how to
merge or combine the changes
into a new merge commit. So here
on the master branch, we type
Git merge, feature slash change
password. Once again, we have a
default message for the merge
commit, we can accept it as is
or change it if we need to. So
let's close this window. Now
back in the terminal, as you can
see, we don't have a fast
forward merge. Now let's look at
our history one more time.
So here's the result of the
merge. Our Change
Password branch is pointing at
this commit.
Our Master was here. Now we
combine these two into a new
merge commit over here.