Welcome to my ultimate git
mastery course. Over the next
five hours, you're going to
learn everything you need to
know to use git like a pro, and
work effectively with others.
We're going to start off by
talking about the fundamental
concepts like what is git, how
to install and configure it. And
then in each section, we're
gonna explore a different set of
git tools will cover creating
snapshots of your code, browsing
your project history, branching
and merging, collaborating with
others using GitHub and
rewriting history. I'm Mosh
Hamedani and I'm super excited
to be your instructor! Now let's
jump in and get started.