Alright, before we get started,
let me tell you something super
important real quick. If you
want to get the most out of this
Git course and become a git
expert, you should watch every
lesson in order. Don't skip any
lessons, even if you think you
know the basics. And trust me,
there's a lot of bad information
and misconceptions about Git out
there. A lot of people don't
know how Git really works. And
that's why they constantly screw
things up and jump on Stack
Overflow for help. I don't want
you to be one of them. So I've
put tremendous effort into
creating this course, to make
sure you really understand how
Git works and how you can use it
like a pro. But that would only
happen if you watch every single
lesson in order. This course is
short and sweet. It's only five
hours long, but teaches you a
ton. You know me I'm not going
to waste your time with bs. With
that, now let's move on to the
next lesson.