So what is Git? And why is it so
popular? Git is the most popular
version control system in the
world. A version control system
records the changes made to our
code over time, in a special
database called repository, we
can look at our project history
and see who has made, what
changes, when and why. And if we
screw something up, we can
easily revert our project back
to an earlier state. Without a
version control system will have
to constantly store copies of
the entire project in various
folders. This is very slow and
doesn't scale at all, especially
if multiple people have to work
on the same project, you will
have to constantly toss around
the latest code by email or some
other mechanisms, and then
manually merge the changes. So
in a nutshell, with a version
control system, we can track our
project history and work
together. Now, version control
systems fall into two
categories, centralized and
distributed. In a centralized
system, all team members connect
to a central server to get the
latest copy of the code, and to
share the changes with others.
So version and Microsoft Team
Foundation Server are examples
of centralized version control
systems. The problem with the
centralized architecture is the
single point of failure. If the
server goes offline, we cannot
collaborate or save snapshots of
our project. So we have to wait
until the server comes back
online. In distributed systems,
we don't have these problems.
Every team member has a copy of
the project with his history on
their machine, so we can save
snapshots of our project locally
on our machine. If the central
server is offline, we can
synchronize our work directly
with others. Git and Mercurial
are examples of distributed
version control systems. Out of
all these, Git is the most
popular version control system
in the world because it's free,
open source, super fast and
scalable. Operations like
branching and merging are slow
and painful in other version
control systems, like subversion
or TFS. But they're very fast
in Git we'll talk about this
ater. So Git is almost
verywhere. More than 90% of
oftware projects in the world
se Git. That's why almost every
ob description for software
eveloper mentions Git. So if
ou're looking for a job as a
oftware developer Git is one of
the skills you must have on yo
r resume. You should know it in
ide out. You should know how it
works, and how to use it to tr
ck your project history and co
laborate with others ef
ectively. And that's exactly wh
t you're going to learn in th
s course.