Let's talk about various ways to
use Git. We can use Git on the
command line. So we open a
terminal or command prompt
window to execute Git commands.
This is the fastest, and
sometimes the easiest way to get
the job done. That's why a lot
of people use the command line.
If you don't like the command
line, Well, you're in luck.
Because most modern code editors
on IDs have built in support for
basic Git features. For example,
in VS code, we have the source
control panel, which gives us
the essential Git features.
There are also extensions
available for bringing
additional Git features. For VS
code. The most popular extension
is GitLance. It brings a ton of
Git features and VS code.
They're also graphical user
interfaces specifically made for
using Git. Here are the Git
websites you can find the
complete list of these tools for
different platforms. We have
tools for Windows, Mac, Linux,
Android and iOS. Out all these,
the two most popular tools are
GitKraken in source tree.
GitKraken  is my personal
Favorite GUI tool. Forget, it's
beautifully designed. It works
across different platforms. And
it integrates with other
GitKraken  products, such as
GitKraken  boards for issue
tracking, and GitKraken
timelines for project
management. It's free for open
source projects. But for
commercial projects, you have to
pay an annual fee. Just to let
you know, I'm not an affiliate
of GitKraken , I'm just a fan.
The other option is source tree.
It's completely free, but it's
only available for Windows and
Mac. So if you're a Linux user,
you have to use GitKraken  or
another GUI tool. In this
course, we'll be spending most
of our time on the command line
for a couple of reasons. The
first reason is that pretty much
all of these GUI tools have some
limitations. They support the
Git commands that people use
most of the time. So even if you
want to use a GUI tool, there
are times you would have to roll
up your sleeves and get back to
the command line to get the job
done. And the other reason is
that the command line is always
available, but there are
situations where a GUI tool may
not be available to you. You
might connect to a server
remotely
And he may not have permission
to install a GUI tool. If you
don't know how to use the
command line, then you're stuck.
In practice, a lot of people,
including myself, use both the
command line and a GUI tool. And
that's what I'm going to show
you in this course, there are
times that it really makes sense
to use a GUI tool and another
command line. But there are
other times that using the
command line is faster and
easier. So we'll use the command
line. At the end of the day, you
should use the right tool for
the job. Don't be like this guy.
You probably know him, our
popular superstar developer
called John Smith. He thinks
he's better than everyone else,
because he does everything in
the command line. He never uses
a GUI tool and he looks down at
people who do, well let him thin
whatever he wants, if that'
what makes him happy, who cares
So we'll be spending most of ou
time on the command line. Bu
when it makes sense to use a GU
tool, I'll be showing yo
examples in VS code and Gi
Kraken because those are the m
st popular tools. Now if y
u've never worked with a c
mmand line before, don't w
rry, I'm going to hold your h
nds and teach you everything s
ep by step. It's a lot easier t
an you think.
Next we're going to install Git