Alright, let's see if you have
Git on your machine or not. And
if yes, what version you have in
stock. To do this, you have to
open a terminal or command
prompt window. If you're on Mac,
press Command space, and then
type terminal. If you're on
Windows, click the Search icon
on the bottom navigation bar and
type cmd. So here's my terminal
or console window, your terminal
window might look different, it
doesn't matter. This is where
we're going to execute Git
commands. So let's look at the
version of Git on this machine.
We type Git dash dash version.
So on this machine, I'm using
Git version 2.19.2. But the late
t version, at the time of recor
ing this video is 2.27.0. So I
highly encourage you to
download and install the late
t version. Just head over to git
SCM comm/downloads. Over here,
ou can find instructions for
nstalling Git on different opera
ing systems. It's really e
sy, you're not gonna have
ny problems. Now if you'r
on Windows, once you inst
ll Git you're going this appl
cation called git bas
, which is short for born ag
in shell. This is basically a c
mmand prompt window like t
is one over here, but it emulat
s Unix or Linux environments.
o throughout this course, I en
ourage you to use Git Bas
instead of the built in comm
nd prompt window. So what you s
e on the screen looks closer t
what I'm going to show you i
this course. So go ahead and
install Git. In the next les
on, I'm going to show you how to
customize our Git environmen
.