Let me show you a few different
ways to get help about Git
commands. Let's say you want to
learn more about the config
command, you can simply google
Git config. On this page, you
can see the full documentation
of this command, you can see
various options and how they
work. We can also access the
same page on the terminal
window, we simply type Git
config, dash dash help. This is
exactly the same information you
saw a second ago. Here, we can
press space to go to the next
page, and cue to exit. Now if
you don't need a full blown
help, just a quick refresher,
you can type Git config dash H
and this gives us a short
summary of this command and its
options.