So you'll learn how to get the
status of the working directory
and the staging area using the
status command. The output of
this command is very
comprehensive, but it's also
very wordy. So as an
alternative, we can supply the
short status flag or dash s. Let
me walk you through a few
examples. So for this demo,
we're going to modify one of our
existing files, and then add a
new file. So Eiko sky, to file
one dot j, s, so we're appending
a sky to file on the J s. Now
let's create a new file. So once
again, Aiko sky to file to the J
s. Now let's run git status. We
have modified five one, and we
have a new untracked file. So as
you can see, the output of this
command is very comprehensive,
but also very wordy. Now, let's
run git status dash s. This is
much easier to dies. So let me
show you how this works. Here we
have two columns. The left
column represents the staging
area The right column represents
the working directory. So we
have modified file one. And
that's why we haven't read em in
the right column, which is the
working directory. So we have
some changes here. But these
changes are not in the staging
area. That's why we don't have
anything in the left column. Now
file three is a new file. That's
why we have two question marks
in both this columns. Now, let's
add file one to the staging
area. So get Add File one, and
then do another short status.
Look. For file one, we have a
green m in the left column or
the staging area column. So all
the changes that we had in the
working area are now in the
staging area. in the right
column, we don't have anything
we don't have any extra changes.
That earlier in this section, I
told you that made me a stage of
file, get takes a snapshot of
that file and puts it in the
staging area. So if we modify
that file after we have to
restate the changes, let me show
you this one more time. So I
want to modify a file one more
time. Let's echo ocean to File
one dot j s, and then run git
status dash s, look what we have
here. So in the left column, we
have a green arrow, which means
we have some changes in the
staging area, we have some
additional changes in the
working directory that are not
added to the staging area. Okay,
so let's add file one to the
staging area one more time. And
then run git status dash rats,
the all the changes that we had
in the working directory are now
in the staging area. So we're
done with file one. Let's look
at file two. So I'm going to add
file two to the staging area as
well. And then run git status
dash s. For file two, we haven't
green a in the left column,
which represents added. So file
two is added and file one is
modified and this is how the
short status output works.