We've made a few commits so far.
But where are these commits? Let
me show you. So we use the lock
command to look at our history.
Take a look. So here are all the
commits we have created, sorted
from the latest to the earliest.
So here's our last commit on
top. Each commit has a unique
identifier. This is a 40
character, hexadecimal string
that gets automatically
generates for us. You can think
of it like a revision number,
but unlike a revision number, it
doesn't increase. It's just a
unique identifier. Okay. Now
next to that we have head
pointing to master. What is
this? Well, we're going to talk
about this a lot in the future.
But Master is the main branch or
the main line of working get in
some other version control
systems. It's called trunk and
get we can have multiple
branches. So we can work on
multiple features or multiple
bug fixes in parallel, and then
combine our code. We'll talk
about that later in the course.
Now head is a reference to the
current branch. So this is how
Git knows one branch we're
currently working on. Again,
we're going to talk about this a
lot in the future. Now for each
commit, you can see the author,
the name of the author, as well
as their email, the date and
time the commit was created, as
well as the one line
description. Like here, we have
multiple commits that are spread
across multiple pages, we can
press space to go to the next
page. And again, now to quit, we
can press Q. Now the lock
command has a few interesting
options. One of them is one
line. This shows us a short
summary of the commands. So here
we have the unique identifier
that is shortened to seven
characters, and we only have the
one line description, so we
don't have the author as well as
the date and time of each
commit. We have another option
for reversing the sort order.
Let me show you. So git log one
line, and then we add dash dash,
reverse. Now we can see the
first command be on top and
here's the last command. Now the
lock command is very powerful.
So in the future, we're going to
talk a lot about it. In fact, we
have a complete section on
browsing history. I'm going to
show you various ways to get
reports from the history. For
now, let's just stick to the
basics.