So viewing the list of commits
is great. But what if we want to
see what exactly we have changed
in a given commit, that's when
we use the show command. For
example, let's say we want to
look at the content of this
commit over here, we type Git
show. Now here, we need to
specify the commit, we want to
inspect, there are two ways to
reference a commit, we can
reference it using its unique
identifier. So we type d, 601,
B, 9 0. Now we don't have to
type all the seven characters,
we can type fewer characters, as
long as we don't have another
commit, whose ID starts with
these characters. So that's one
way to reference a commit. And
another way is to use the head
pointer. So look, head is
currently in front of the last
commit. So to view the last
commit, we can type head or to
look at previous commit, we can
type a till there, and then
specify how many steps we want
to go back. So if we type one,
we start from head which is
here, we go one step back, and
this References This comment
over here. Let's take a look. So
on the top, we can see the
author and the date of this
commit, as well as its message.
Below that we have a diff of
what has changed. So in this
commit, we have changed a single
file that is git ignore. Over
here, we can see that we removed
this line and added these two
lines. So this is very useful.
Now what if we don't want to see
the differences, we want to see
the final version, the exact
version that is stored in this
commit? Well, you bring up the
last command, get show head till
the one. Then we type a colon.
And here we specified the full
path to a file. For example, we
can say, dot Git ignore or if
this file is in a subdirectory.
We type for example, bin slash
app dot bin Okay, now let's look
at Git ignore. So this is the
exact version stored in this
commit. Now, earlier I told you
that each commit contains a
complete snapshot of our working
directory, not just changes, but
when we run the show command. We
only see the differences? What
is changed? What if you want to
see all the files and
directories in a commit? Well,
for that, we're gonna use a
different command. That's called
LS tree. Now why is this called
a tree, well, it tree is a data
structure for representing
hierarchical information. So in
a tree, we can have nodes, and
these nodes can have children.
Now directory on the file system
can be represented using a tree.
Because each directory can have
children, these children can be
files, and other sub
directories. If you want to
learn more about this concept,
you should take my dat
structures course. So LS tree m
ans list all the files in a t
ee. Now here we specified the c
mments we're interested in had t
lde one. And now look, these a
e all the files and d
rectories stored in this c
mmit. So we have Git ignore. R
ght before that we have a u
ique identifier that is g
nerated based on the content o
this file. So in gits d
tabase. We have an object with t
is ID. Below that we have b
en, again, it has a unique i
entifier that is generated b
sed on the content of this d
rectory, now look at the type o
this object, it's a tree. So f
les are represented using b
obs, and directories are r
presented using trees. All of t
ese are objects that are s
ored in gits database. Using t
e show command, we can easily v
ew an object and gits d
tabase. For example, if we t
pe Git show, and then specify t
is unique identifier, or we c
n type only the few c
aracters, as long as there is n
ambiguity. So here's the c
ntent of our Git ignore file. A
another example, let's look a
this object, this tree, the b
n directory, so git show 6
629. Here we have a tree. In t
is tree, we have this file, a
p dot bin. So using the show co
mand, we can view an object an
gets database. These objects ca
be commits, blobs, which re
resent files, and trees which re
resent directories, as well as
tags. We'll talk about tags in
the future.