So I told you that you should
always review the stuff that you
have in the staging area before
making a commit. So let's say we
review this changes. And we
realize that the changes in file
one shouldn't go in the next
commit, perhaps because these
changes are logically part of a
different task. So we don't want
to have a commit that represents
changes for different tasks,
right. So in this case, we want
to undo the Add operation,
because earlier, we use the Add
command to Add File one to the
staging area. Now we're going to
undo this operation. How do we
do this? Well, in the past, we
used the reset command. But a
lot of people found this command
confusing, especially with
options such as hard or soft.
That's why we have a new command
called restore. Now make sure
you're using the latest version
of Git. Otherwise, what I'm
going to show you is not going
to work on your machine. So here
I'm using Git version 2.28. And
with this we can easily restore
files in different environments,
in working directory or In the
staging area, so git restore,
you're going to restore file one
in the staging area. So we type
dash dash staged. And then we
specify the file name, we can
list multiple files here, we can
also use patterns. Or if you
want to restore everything in
the staging area, we simply use
a period. So here I'm going to
restore file one dot j s. Now,
when we run git status, again,
you're not going to see a green
m here, because all the changes
that we had in the staging area
are now in the working
directory. Take a look. So git
status dash s. Look, we no
longer have any changes for file
one in the staging area. All the
changes are in the working
directory, it's essential for
you to understand how the
Restore command works. The
restore command essentially
takes the copy from the next
environment. So in case of the
staging environment, what is the
next environment, the last
commit? What do we have in the
repository so When a restored
file one in the staging area,
git took the last copy of this
file from the last snapshot and
put it in the staging area. That
is what happened. Now look at
file two file two is a new file,
because here we have a green A,
which is short for added. So we
have this file, we have this new
file in the staging area, but
this file doesn't exist in the
last commit. So what do you
think will happen whenever you
store this file? Well, because
we don't have a copy of this
file in our repository or in our
last commit, Git is going to
remove this file from the
staging area and take it back to
its previous state, which is a
new untracked file. Let me show
you. So git restore dash dash
staged file to the J s. Now,
let's run git status again. So
file two is a new untracked file
because we have two question
marks.