There are times that we have
some code in our working
directory that we want to throw
away. Let's say we made some
changes, but we didn't like
those changes. So we want to
scratch everything and start
over, we can discard the local
changes using the Restore
command. So here we have some
local changes in file one dot j,
s. To undo this changes, we type
Git restore, file one dot j s,
when we execute this command,
Git is going to take the version
of this file in the next
environment, which is our
staging environment, it's going
to take that version and copy
into our working directory. We
can also use a period here, and
this will undo all the local
changes. Now let me show you
something. So the command is
executed. Now let's run another
short status. But file two is
still here. Why is that? Well,
this is a new untracked file. So
Git hasn't been tracking this.
So when we tell Git to reassert
this file, git doesn't know
where to get a previous version
of his file. It doesn't exist in
our staging environment or In
our repository, so, to remove
all these new untracked files,
we have to type git clean. Take
a look. By default, we get this
fatal error saying required for
us to false to true. And neither
of these searches are given. So
basically git us telling us that
hey, this is a dangerous
operation. If you accidentally
remove this on track files,
there is no way you can recover
them. So let's try and git clean
dash H for a quick help. Here we
have this option dash F, which
forces git to remove this on
track fast. You also have dash D
for removing whole directories.
So quite often we type Git clean
dash fd. Now, let's run short
status again. File two is gone.
So this is how we undo local
changes.