So now you know that once Git
tracks a file, it stores every
version of that file in its
database. And that means if you
screw things, we can always
restore a file or a directory to
a previous version. So in this
demo, I'm going to delete a file
and then show you how to restore
it. It's very easy. So we're
going to delete file one dot J
s, I told you that if we use the
rm command in Linux, or Unix
based systems, this will only
remove the file from the working
directory. So then we'll have to
state the change or the
deletion. A better way is to use
the Git rm command. This will
remove the file from both the
working directory as well as the
staging area. Okay. Now let's
get a short status. So in the
staging area, we have a deleted
file. Now, let's make a commit,
delete file one dot J s.
Alright, now let's say shoot, we
shouldn't have deleted this
file. So what can we do here?
Well, we have a few options. We
can undo or revert the last
commit. We're going to talk
about that later in the course.
But in this lesson, I want to
talk about restoring a file to a
previous version, not undoing a
commit. So let's look at our
history. Alright, so here's our
history, we want to restore file
one to the commit before the
last commit, that is coming over
here. So we type Git restore.
Now let's have a quick look at
the documentation. The restore
command takes three types of
arguments, we can supply a bunch
of options, we can supply a
source, you haven't done this so
far. So by default, git will
restore that file from the next
environment or the next area. So
if the file we want to restore
is in the working directory gets
we'll restore it from the
staging area. And if the file is
in the staging area, it will
restore it from the last
snapshot or the last commit. Now
in this case, we want to change
the default behavior. We want to
restore a file from the commit
before the last one. So we type
git restore data source, we set
it to head tilda one. And then
we specify the full path to the
file. In this case, file one dot
j s. Now, let's get a short
status. So we have a new
untracked file. So this is how
we can restore a file to a
previous version.