The first thing we're going to
do is create a directory for our
project. You can call this
directory anything and put it
anywhere on your machine, it
doesn't matter. I'm currently in
the projects directory. So let's
create a directory called moon,
and then go into this directory.
So let's imagine this is our
project directory. and here we
can have 10s, or hundreds of
files.
The first time we want to add
this file to a git repository,
we have
to initialize a new empty
repository. So we type Git in
it, look at this message,
initialized, empty Git
repository in and here's the
full path. So we have the moon
directory. And inside this
directory, we have a
subdirectory called dot Git.
And, by default, this
subdirectory is hidden because
you're not supposed to touch it.
So if we type ls to list all the
files and directories here, we
don't see anything. But if you
type ls dash A, which is short
for all, we can see the Git sub
directory If you're on Mac, you
can open this with Finder. And
if you're on Windows, you can
open it with Windows Explorer or
File Explorer. I'm not sure why
it's called these days. So let's
open .git take a look.
So here's our Git directory or
Git repository. This is where
Git stores information about our
project history. So we have
directories like branches,
hooks, info, objects, and
references. Now someone using
Git, you don't really need to
understand this structure. This
is purely implementation detail.
It's how Git stores information.
It's none of our business.
That's why this directory is
hidden so you don't touch it. If
you corrupt or remove this
directory, you're gonna lose
your project history. Let me
show you. So back in the
terminal, look at this green
marker. It says Git that means
we have a git repository in this
directory. Now if you want to
have a pretty colorful terminal
window like this on mac you need
to install zelis H or z shell
and on Windows, you need to
install poshkit but don't worry
about it. Now, these tools are
completely optional to use. Git
is just for making things
pretty. So here we have a git
repository. Now, if I remove the
Git subdirectory, we're going to
lose this repository. So RM dash
RF .Git, look, the green mar
er is gone. We don't have a git
repository here anymore. So don
t touch this directory. Now once
again, let's initialize a Git
repository. Beautiful. So now
that we have a repository. Next
we're going to talk about the
basic Git workflow.