Now let's look at the git tools
built in to GitKracken. So here
on the homepage of GitKracken,
we go to open a repository.
Here, we can open an existing
repository. We can also clone a
repository. I'm going to talk
about that in the future. But
this is basically useful when we
have a repository somewhere
else. Let's see on GitHub, and
you want to take a copy of the
repository and put it on our
machine. Again, we're going to
talk about this in the future.
We can also initialize a new
repository. For this demo, I'm
going to open our moon
repository. So open repository,
go to our folder, and then open,
good. So over here we can see
all the commits we have created
so far, we can see the author of
each commit, the commit message,
and the date and time when the
commit was created. Now we can
click on each commit to see more
details. So for this commit, we
can see the commit ID. Here's
the commit message, the author,
date and time and the summary of
changes. So in this commit, we
added one new file, which is
file one dot j s. Here we have
multiple views, we have the list
view and tree view. If you have
changed multiple files in
different folders, tree view is
very helpful. We can also select
View All files, to see all the
files in our project. At this
point in time, if you uncheck
this, we only see the change
bias. And by change, I'm talking
about additions, modifications
and deletions. Now we can click
on each file to get a diff of
that file. So once again, we're
dealing with a new file here.
That's why we don't have any
code on the left side. Here we
have two tabs, the feel and file
view. If we switch to file view,
we can see the snapshot of this
file in this commit at this
point in time. Now, let's go
back to diff view. We also have
different ways of comparing the
changes. So currently, we're
looking at the split view, which
gives us the before and after
code. We also have a line view,
which is exactly like what we
get on the terminal. We also
have hunk view If you're dealing
with a large file with a bunch
of changes in different parts of
this file hunk view is an easy
way to see the changes in
ach section. Now let's make a
new commit. So we have to go bac
to VS code or our favorite ed
tor to make the changes. Because
GitKracken is just a GUI too
. It's not a code editor. So I
m going to go back to VS cod
, open file one dotJ s and write
a new line of code here, save t
e changes. Now, back in
GitKracken let's close thi
window. Over here, you can se
we have one change in ou
working directory. We can clic
on this button to view th
changes. So file one dot js i
changed. And currently it'
unstaged. We can click on thi
file to see a summary of th
changes. So this is the new lin
that we have introduced
Beautiful. Now we can go ove
here and stage this file o
stage all changes. Now this fil
isn't a staging area. If we mad
a mistake, we can always ask O
stage this file, super easy. So
let's save the file and the
type a commit message, let's sa
refactor code. And now let'
make a new commit. It's a
simple as that. So this is ho
we can use GitKracken to create
snapshots of our project, but
there is a lot more to Git
racken and we're going to c
ver that in the future s
ctions.