Let's start by adding a couple
of files to our project. To do
that, we're gonna use the echo
command. This is not a good
command, it's just a standard
Unix or Linux command for
writing content to a file. So
here we're gonna write hello to
file one dot txt. So here, I'm
working with a txt file. Because
I don't want this course to be
specific to people who know a
particular programming language
like Python or JavaScript. What
I'm going to show you in terms
of the workflow applies to any
programming languages. Okay? So
we write hello to file one dot
txt. Good. Now let's execute
this command one more time, and
change file one to file two. So
now we have two files in our
project. Now look at this
question mark here. That means
we have new files here that are
not tracked by git, because the
first time you initialize a git
repository in a directory, Git
is not going to automatically
track your files. So if you have
1000 files in a project, you
have to instruct Git to track
them. Okay. So here we go. run
git status to see the status of
the working directory on the
staging area. Take a look. So we
don't have any comments yet. We
have untracked files, which are
file one and file two. They're
indicated by red because they're
not in the staging area yet. To
add these files to the staging
area, we use the git add
command. Here we can list a
single file, like file one dot
txt, or multiple files separated
by a space. We can also use
patterns. So star dot txt, that
means all the files with a txt
extension, we also have period,
which adds the entire directory
recursively. But you have to be
a little bit careful with this.
Because sometimes there are
files you don't want to add to
your repository, perhaps large
files like large binary files or
lock files, you don't want to
add this faster repository,
because they increase the size
of your repository. I will show
you how to ignore this files
later in this section. So just
remember, add period adds the
entire directory recursively in
this demo, I'm going to go with
this command, because we only
have two files in this
directory, okay? Now our green
indicator change to yellow,
which means we have stuff in the
staging area that are ready to
be committed. So if we run git
status again, look, we have two
new files, and they're indicated
by green, which means they're in
the staging area. Now, let me
show you something interesting.
I'm going to modify a file one.
So once again, we're gonna use
the echo command to echo world.
But here instead of one greater
than sign, I'm going to use two
greater than signs, which means
a pet. So we're going to append
world to file one dot txt. Now
let's run git status again, look
what happened. We have two files
in the staging area, because
they're indicated by green. But
we also have one modified file
in our working directory. So you
might be asking, but hey, Marsh,
didn't we already Add File one
to staging area? Yes, we did.
But when you run the Add
command, get took a snapshot of
file one And out of that
snapshot to the staging area. So
here's the current situation. In
the staging area, we have the
first version of file one, we
change this file after we added
it to the staging area. So what
we currently have in our working
directory is the second version
of this file. It has some
changes that are not staged yet.
So back to the terminal. We run
git add period or git add file
one dot txt one more time. Now
look at the status of our
working directory. Both these
files are in the staging area,
and we don't have any unstaged
changes. So next, I'm going to
show you how to commit this
snapshot to permanently store it
in our Git repository.