Now we have a snapshot in the
staging area ready to be
permanently stored in our
repository. So we type git
commit, dash M for message. And
here in double quotes, we type a
short description that
identifies what this snapshot
represents. So here I'm going to
say, initial commit. Now there
are times that a short one line
description is not sufficient.
You want to explain some details
to give context. For example, if
you worked on a bug, and there
were some constraints at the
time you committed your code,
you want to explain those
constraints. This is very
valuable to both you and your
coworkers. So in situations like
this, we drop the message. We
just type git commit. Now when
we press enter, this opens our
default editor, in this case VS
code, because at the beginning
of the course, I configured my
default editor to be VS code.
Okay. So here we're trying to
edit this file, commit,
underlined edit message which
stored in our Git subdirectory.
So, on the top, we can type a
short description. Ideally,
there should be less than 80
characters, and then we add a
line break. And after that we
can type a long description. Now
this lines that start with a
pound sign or comments, they're
gonna get ignored. So we typed
what everyone here in this case,
I'm going to say, initial
command. And this is our first
commit. Of course, this is
repetitive. We don't have commit
messages like this. But for this
demo, I'm going to go with this
message. So we save the changes.
Then, we close this window. Back
in the terminal, our snapshot is
committed. And here we have
basic statistics about what was
changed. So two files were
changed which are file one and
file two. And we have three
insertions, three lines were
inserted. In file one, we
inserted two lines, hello world,
and in file, two inserted one
line. Now look at this
indicator, it turned green,
because our working directory is
Now clean, it doesn't have any
new changes. So what we have in
our working directory is exactly
the same content we have in our
staging area, which is exactly
the same content we have in the
last commit.