Let's talk about the best
practices for committing code.
First of all your commits
shouldn't be too big or too
small. We don't want to make a
commit, every time we update a
file, that's just useless.
Because we'll end up with
commits like update five, one
update file to occupy three,
it's just useless. On the other
hand, we don't want our commits
to be too big, we don't want to
wait and implement a feature end
to end before committing it. We
don't want to code for three
days and then make a commit,
because the whole point of
committing is to record
checkpoints as we go. So if you
screw up, we can always go back
and recover our code. So try to
commit often, in the real world,
you might commit five to 10
times a day or even more,
depending on the kind of work
you're doing. But this is just a
basic guideline. Don't take it
as a rule. Don't try to aim for
five or 10 commits a day. So as
you're coding, as you reach a
state you want to record then
make a commit. And also, each
commit should represent a
logically separate chain set. So
don't mix things up. For
example, if you're fixing a bug,
and then you accidentally Find a
typo in your app, you shouldn't
come in both this changes in one
commit, you should have two
separate commits, one commit for
the typo, another one for the
bug fix. Now, if you
accidentally stage both these
changes, we can easily onstage
them. I'll show you how to do
this later in the section. Next,
you should give yourself the
habit of creating meaningful
commit messages. Because all of
these messages are going to show
up in history. So if your
messages are cryptic, they're
not going to be helpful to you
or other team members. If you
follow my previous advice, if a
commit represents a single unit
of work, it would be easier to
come up with a message for your
commit. If you're doing too many
things in one commit, you're not
going to come up with a good
message. Okay. Now in terms of
the wording, most people prefer
to use the present tense in
their commit messages. So
instead of fixed a bug, you
should say, fixed a bug. If you
don't like this convention,
that's totally fine. But
whatever commercial use, make
sure that you and other team
members stick to it. So always
take this best practices in mind
when committing code