One of the common questions a
lot of beginners have is, do we
always have to state our changes
before committing them? Well,
the answer is no. And in this
video, I'm going to show you how
to skip the staging area. But do
this only if you know what
you're doing. If you're 100%
sure that your code your changes
don't need to be reviewed,
because that's the whole point
of having a staging area. So
let's modify find one and then
committed in one step. We're
going to say echo test to file
one dot txt. Once again, we're
appending this line to file one
dot txt, okay. All right. Now
that we have a yellow indicator,
because our working directory is
dirty, so instead of running git
add, and then committing an in
two steps, we're going to
commit. Here we're going to
supply the option dash a which
means all that means all modify
files, and then just like before
we supply a message, or we can
combine these two options. So a
supplier to fix the bug that
prevented the users from signing
up. Let's go. Our code is
committed. One file was changed,
and we have one insertion. So
this is how we can skip the
staging area. But once again, do
this only if you know what
you're doing 99% of the time,
you should always state your
code before committing into the
repository.