Let's say that we just
discovered that we no longer
need file to in our project
because it contains unused code.
So to remove this file, we type
RM file to the txt. Again, this
is not a good command because it
doesn't start with Git. It's
just a standard Unix command.
Okay, so let's go with this. Now
we have a yellow indicator,
which means our working
directory is dirty. So let's run
git status. We have one change
that is not staged for commit.
So we remove file two from our
working directory, but still
exists in the staging area. Let
me prove it to you. So we type
git, LS dash files. These are
the files in our staging area.
So file two still here, even
though we removed it from our
working directory. So as I told
you before, every time we make
changes, we have to stage those
changes using the Add command.
So here we type git add file to
the txt to stage this change or
this deletion more, actually
accurately. Now let's run git LS
slash files one more time. So
file two is no longer in the
staging area. Beautiful. Let's
run git status, we have one
change that is ready to be
committed. And as you can see,
it's indicated by green, which
means it's in the staging area.
So let's commit this change. And
here we're going to say, remove
unused code. So to remove a
file, we have to remove it from
both our working directory as
well as the staging area.
Because this is a very common
operation, git gives us a
command that does both of these
steps in one go. Let me show
you. So we type Git RM. So
instead of using the standard rm
command in Unix, we use Git Rm
karolis, the file name, like
file two dot txt, we can also
specify multiple files. We can
also use patterns like all text
files. When we execute this
command, git remote this file
from both the working directory
as well as the staging area.