One of the great but also
dangerous features of Git is
that it allows us to rewrite our
history. We can drop or modify
commits, we can combine or split
them. And so that's what we're
going to talk about in this
section. We're going to start
off by talking about why and
when to rewrite history. Then
I'm going to show you how to
undo or revert commits. You
already covered these before,
but we're going to revisit them
with a bit more depth. Next,
we're going to learn how to use
interactive rebasing to rewrite
history. With interactive
rebasing, we can modify commits,
drop them, combine or split them
and so on. We're also going to
talk about recovering, lost
commits. There are a lot of fun
things we're going to talk
about. So let's jump in and get
started.