Now let's see how we can drop a
commit. So let's say we want to
drop this commit over here, our
first work in progress. But
before doing so let's look at
the content of this commit. So
I'm going to copy the commit ID.
Now, let's run git shell.
Alright, and this commit, we
introduced a new file called
terms. txt. And in this file, we
added this line, draft. Now
let's look at the next commit.
So back to the log.
Here's the next commit, update
Terms of Service.
So once again, let's look at the
content of this commit,
git show. Here, we have two
changes, we have an update in
package dot txt. So we're
updating Google Map version. We
also have a change in terms of
txt. So we replaced draft with
completed. Okay. So here's the
interesting part. Let's pull up
the history one more time. What
do you think will happen? If we
try to drop this commit, we're
going to end up with a conflict.
Here's the reason why dropping
this commit, we're essentially
saying, we never introduced this
change. So we never introduced a
file called terms dot txt. Now
in contrast, the next commit
says, Hey, I have an update for
terms dot txt, so Git will not
be able to replay all these
commits, it's going to get
confused. This is where we need
to jump in, resolve the
conflict, and then continue the
rebase operation.
So here's the commit you want to
drop, we should
start our rebase operation with
the parent of this commit. So we
type Git rebase dash I, here's
the commit, then we type tilda
ne, or we can also use a
arrot, that means the parent.
o let's go with that. Here's
he commit on a drop, we can
hange the command from pick to
rop. Or I can just delete the
lide. Now save the changes and
ack in the terminal. Alright,
ook, we have a conflict.
But don't get scared.
This is much easier than you
think. So let's run a short
status. What's going on here, we
have some changes in the staging
area, we have an update to
package dot txt, and we have
some local changes that are not
staged. On the one hand, we are
trying to delete this file. On
the other hand, we're trying to
update it. So these changes that
you see here, are actually going
to go with the next commit. So
let's pull up the history one
more time. All right, look, the
head is currently at this
location. So it's in the
detached mode, we told get that
we want to drop this commit. So
Git is trying to undo the
changes introduced in this
commit. In this case, adding
this new file terms of txt. Now
the changes that we have in the
staging area are going to go
when replaying the next commit.
And this commit, we have two
changes, we updated Terms of
Service and Google Map SDK
version. So now we need to
resolve the conflict. We type
Git merge tool, we have two
types of changes and deletion
and a modification. In this
case, we're going to go with the
modification, because we want to
keep that file in our history.
So let's go with that. Now,
let's get a short status again.
So we have two changes in the
staging area that are going to
go with the next commit. So we
were ready to continue the
rebase operation. Git rebase
dash dash, continue. Also, as I
told you before, if you screw
something up or if you have a
nasty merge conflict, you can
always abort and go back to the
state before you started the
rebase operation.
It's very easy. So let's
continue rebasing.
Alright, here's the message for
the next commit update Terms of
Service and Google Map SDK. So
let's close that. We're done
with rebasing beautiful, let's
look at our history more time.
So our first work in progress
commit is gone.
Now as another example, I want
to drop these two commits as
ell. So these are the last
hree commits, we can run
git rebase dash, I
head tilda three.
So we said the last three
commits. Now I'm going to
elete these two commits and s
ve the changes back in the t
rminal. In this case, we d
dn't have any conflicts.
So let's look at our history one
last time.
All those ugly commits are gone.
Next, I'm going to show you how
to reward commit messages.