Now let's see how we can rework
commit messages. So earlier I
told you that here we have a
wording issue, render
restaurants on the map, so the
word on is missing.  Once again
we're going to start interactiv
rebasing. So I'm going to gra
this commit ID. Now let's run
it rebase dash i, this commit ca
rot to represent its parent. Al
right, here's the commit you w
nt to reward. Now, we're going t
replace their pick command w
th reword. We can also reword m
ltiple commits. For example, l
t's say here, we forgot to i
clude the Google Map SDK v
rsion. So I'm going to use the r
word commit here as well. Go
d. Now, when I close this wi
dow, it will replay each of th
se commits. For every commit tha
you want to reword, it's goi
g to stop and give us a cha
ce to change the message. So clo
e. Alright, here's the first com
it you wanted to reword. So rend
r restaurants on the map. Good
save, close, get replayed the
ther comments, and then he stop
ed at this second commit we want
d to reword. So here I'm goin
to add the version save, clos
. And rebasing was succ
ssful, beautiful. Now let's pull
up the history. Now, I want to e
phasize this one more time. In t
is demo, we reworded this comm
t, which caused this commit to b
recreated, and that means all
he subsequent commits are also
recreated. So we have writ
en history as a total befo
e rewriting history is a dest
uctive operation. You shou
d do this only with the comm
ts in your local repo
itory. Next, I'm going to show
you how to reorder commits.