Earlier we talked about the
problem with this commit, add a
reference to Google Map SDK. The
problem with this commit is its
position in the history, because
we're adding a reference to
Google Map after implementing a
feature that is dependent on
google map. So if you check out
this commit, and reinstall our
pplication to this point, our
pplication is not going to
ork. Because at this point in
ime, in this snapshot, we don't
ave a reference to Google Map.
o in this demo, we're going to
rab this commit and move it
own. It's super easy. So once
gain, we want to start our
ebase operation. So I'm going
o grab the ID of this commit,
o we can see all the commits in
ur rebase script. Git rebase,
ashI. Good. So we can see all of
our commits from the oldest to
the newest. Now I'm going to gr
b this command, add a re
erence and move it up. In VS co
e, we can move a line up by pr
ssing ALT and the up arrow. So
like this, now this commit is in
the right position. So save th
changes, close. Rebasing co
pleted successfully. Now le
's look at the log one more ti
e. So first, we add a re
erence to Google Map, and th
n we render restaurants on th
map. This is much better, bu
we're not done yet. In the ne
t lesson, I'm going to show yo
how to squash a few commits tog
ther.