Now look at these three commits,
render restaurants on the map,
fix a typo, and change the color
of restaurant icons. All these
changes are logically part of
the same unit of work. So
ideally, we should have
encapsulated all these changes
inside a single snapshot. But
sometimes that's not possible,
because we work incrementally.
And as we learn more about a
problem, our solution changes.
So we end up with several
commits that are logically part
of the same unit of work. So
let's see how we can combine
these commits together. So
here's the first commit we want
to work on, we're going to start
with the parent of this commit,
which is this commit over here.
So copy this, git rebase dash I.
Alright, so here's our first
commit render restaurants on the
map. For the second command, I'm
going to replace the pig command
with squash. With this, I guess
we'll combine this commit with
the previous commit. Now for the
third commit, once again, we're
going to use the squash command
to combine this commit with the
previous commit, which is the
combination of these two
commits. Now if the commits that
we want to squash are not
directly next to each other, we
can reorder them first, and then
squash them. So let's save the
changes and close. Now, Git is
suggesting this commit message,
which is the combination of the
messages for all these three
commits. So we have render
restaurants on the map, fix a
typo and change the color, I'm
going to discard this commit
messages and keep the original
message, save, close. And we're
done with the rebase operation.
Let's look at our history. Our
history is much cleaner. Now, we
have a reference to Google Map
SDK. After that, we render
restaurants on the map, then we
update Terms of Service and so
on. Now, we have another command
similar to squash called fix up,
let me show you how it works. So
first, I want to restore our
history to the state before we
started the squash operation. So
we bring up our F log, look what
we have here. The last entry
represents the completion of the
rebase operation. Before that we
had rebase, pick rebase pick
again, followed by a couple of
squashes. And this is where we
started our rebase operation.
Now we want to go to the
previous state in history. So
after we finished the previous
rebase operation, so I'm going
to copy this command ID. Now
let's reset the head. Good. So
to verify, let's look at our
history one more time, we can
see our original commits, like
fix a typo and change the color
of restaurants. Now let's start
the rebase operation one more
time. So I'm going to grab this
coming id
and start an interactive rebase.
So just like before, we're going
to pick that first commit. But
for the second commit, instead
of squash, I'm going to use fix
up. Let me use fix up. Git
doesn't take the message of this
command. So let us fix up for
the third command as well. Same.
Now when I close this, it will
take the message from the first
commit and apply it to the
commit that combines all these
three commits, so we don't have
a chance to craft a new message.
Take a look close is
successfully completed rebasing.
Next I'm going to show you how
to split a commit