Now look at this coming up here,
update Terms of Service and
Google Map SDK version. These
are two completely separate
changes. Updating the Google Map
version has nothing to do with
updating Terms of Service. So we
should split this commit into
two separate commits. So I'm
going to grab this commit ID.
Now we start interactive
rebasing from the parent of this
commit. All right, here, we're
going to use the Edit command
that you have seen before. So
when we close this window, it
will stop the rebase operation
at this commit. Here, we have a
chance to split this commit into
two separate commits. So close
back into terminal. Look, we
stopped at this commit, update
Terms of Service and Google Map
version. Now let's look at the
log one more time. So head is
currently pointing to this
commit. And we can use the reset
command to go back to the state
before we made this commit. So
we can type Git reset, dash die
soft, had tilda one, or head
carrot, and with this, we go one
step back before we made this
commit. So our changes are going
to be in the staging area. and
here we can unstaged some of the
changes and make a separate
commit. Alternatively, we can go
two steps back. So we're going
to onstage our changes, but our
changes are going to be in the
working directory, then we can
stage and commit them
separately, I'm going to go with
this. Also, as I told you
before, mixed as the default
option, so we can simplify this
command to get reset head
carrot. Okay, now, let's get a
short status. So we have two
kinds of changes. We have some
updates in package dot txt, and
a new on track file. So I'm
going to stage package dot txt
and make a commit. here we can
say update Google Map SDK
version. We can also say from
1.0 to 2.0.
All right, now let's look at the
history one more time.
We have divergence. So we
started our rebase operation. At
this commit, we wanted to replay
these two commits now git
stopped before replaying this
command. Here, we added a new
commit. And that's why we have
divergence. Now, let's go ahead
and make another commit for
updating the terms of service.
So we have a new untracked file,
we can add it in the staging
area, and then make a commit.
Here we can say update or add
Terms of Service. Good. So we
made another new commit that was
not part of the history. Let's
look at our log one more time.
So here are the two new commits
that we have created. And this
is the commit that we're trying
to edit. Note that in this demo,
I didn't use the amend option,
because I didn't really want to
amend or modify this commit. I
wanted to replace this commit
with two separate commits. So
now when we continue the rebase
operation, it will replay the
next commit. So Git rebase dash
dash continue radom with
rebasing let's pull up the
history of one last time. So we
have two separate commits, one
for updating Google Map, the
other for adding Terms of
Service. So this is how we can
split the commit