Now let's see how we can rewrite
history using GitKraken. So
here's our mercury repository
that we started with at the
beginning of this section. So
all those bad commits that we
talked about exist here. Now we
want to start an interactive
rebasing from this commit. So we
right click here, and then go to
interactive rebase. So we see a
similar interface. Here, we can
see all the commits listed from
the newest to the oldest. So for
this commit, we can select
rewording and type the new
message here. So render
restaurants on the map update
we're done with this, we ca
move commits around. So here's
the commit that adds a
eference to Google Map, we can
elect this and drop it before
endering the restaurant. We can
lso squash commits. So I want t
squash this commit into this c
mmit. So here we pick squash. An
now we can visually see that th
s commit is going to get co
bined with the previous co
mit. Also, I'm going to sq
ash this commit into the pr
vious commit. Super easy, we ca
also drop a commit. So for th
s commit I'm going to set the
ommand to drop. Now when you
tart the rebase operation, we'r
going to see the same conf
ict as before, because in this
commit, we introduced a new file
terms.txt. If it dropped t
is commit, we're essential
y deleting that file. But then
fter this, we have another c
mmit that tries to update th
t file. So let's go ahead and
start the rebase operation
Alright, we have a conflict.
n the right side, you can see we
have a conflict in terms of t
t. So let's select this. Here
on the top, we have a few option
. We can keep the modified v
rsion or delete the file. In t
is case, we're going to keep th
modified version. So let's go w
th that and then continue r
basing. Good, so we're done
with rebasing that was super
asy, but here we cannot edi
a commit, so we cannot spl
t it into two separate c
mmits or amended. For those case
, you have to go back to the ter
inal.