Let's start off by talking about
why we need to rewrite history.
Well, we have to ask, why do we
need the history in the first
place, we needed to see what was
changed, why, and when, if our
commit messages are not
meaningful, or if our commits
are too large and contain
unrelated changes, or if there
are too small and scattered all
over the history, then we're not
going to be able to extract
meaningful information from the
history. We want a clean,
readable history that tells this
story of our project, how it's
evolved from day one. And that's
where rewriting the history
comes in. If you have small
related commits, we can squash
them into a single commit that
represents a logical chain set.
On the other hand, if you have a
large commit that contains a lot
of unrelated changes, we can
split that commit into a bunch
of smaller commits, each
representing a logically
separate chain set. We can also
reward commit messages so
they're more meaningful. If you
made commits by accident, we can
drop them, we can also modify
the content of our commits. So
if you forgot to include a file
in a commit, we can go back and
modify that commit. These are
the operations we can perform
and get to produce a clean,
readable and meaningful history.
But rewriting history can be a
dangerous operation, and you
need to know what you're doing
before touching the history.
That's what we're going to talk
about next.