So I told you about the benefits
of rewriting history. But before
doing so, you should remember
the golden rule of rewriting
history. Don't rewrite public
history. This basically means if
you have pushed your commits to
share your work with others,
those commits are considered
public, and you should not
modify them. Let me explain why.
Let's say our local and remote
repositories are in the same
state, they have the same
history. And now we want to
modify B. Here's what you need
to understand. Commits and Git
are immutable, which means once
we create them, they cannot be
changed. So if you try to modify
B git, we'll create a new
command, let's call it B star.
So B is going to stay in gets
database, in case we screw
something up, and we want to
recover it later. Now let's say
we want to do a push to share
our change with others. What do
you think is going to happen?
Git is going to reject our push.
Can you tell why? At this level,
you should be able to answer
this question. If not pause the
video, think about it for a few
seconds. Here's the reason. Look
at the shape of our history. On
the left side, our master
branches have diverged. And this
is exactly the same scenario
where we try to push after
someone else has pushed the
origin. So there are some
changes in origin slash master
that don't exist in our master.
In this case, first we have to
merge origin slash master into
our local master. And then we
can do a push. Now, our local
and remote repositories have the
same history. But look at what
we have done here, we have
created this nonlinear noisy
history, these two commits, B
and M are completely
unnecessary. We wanted to modify
B and replace it with something
better. So why should we keep it
in history and shared with
others. So now let's look at an
alternative solution. We're back
in the previous state before we
did a push. So if we do a push,
our push is going to reject
that. Here, we can use the Force
option and force Git to override
what is an origin with what we
have locally. So in origin, Git
is going to drop B and replace
it with B star. And then in our
local repository, Git is going
to attach origin slash master to
B star. Now we have a simple
linear history. So you might
think this is great, we should
use the Force option all the
time. That is not true. This
forget about our local
repository for a second. Imagine
here is John's repository before
we did a push, so john is not
aware of our new commit B star
in his repository, he only has A
and B. So he adds a new commit
on top of B. And then he tries
to do a push, what do you think
is going to happen? You know,
the answer, John's push is going
to get rejected. Because once
again, his master branch is
diverged from origin slash
master. So there are some
changes in origin, in this case,
B star that John doesn't have in
his local repository. So first,
he has to do a pool to bring in
B star and then merge it with
his master. Now he can do a push
to share his work with others.
But look, once again, we have
created this noisy nonlinear
history. So remember, the golden
rule, don't rewrite public
history. Once you push your
work, it's public, it's final.
So you should not change it
unless you have a strong reason
for doing so. rewriting the
private history in your local
repository is perfectly fine.
And in fact, it's actually a
good practice. So you should
always clean up your work or
your private history before
sharing it with the rest of the
world. So back to our
repositories. Currently, both
our local and remote
repositories are in the same
state. Now let's say we add a
new commit on top of being this
new commit is private, because
we haven't shared it with anyone
else. We haven't pushed it yet.
So we can change the commit
message or the content. We can
even drop this commit. No one is
going to get affected