In this section, we're going to
work with a different repository
called mercury. If you want to
follow along with me, you can
get this repository right below
this video. Now, let's look at
our history. So here's our
initial commands. After that we
have render restaurants, the
map, here, we have a warning
issue, that word on is missing.
So the message should have been
render restaurants on the map.
So later, we'll come back and
fix the warning issue. After
that we have fixed a typo. This
is a common issue that I see
quite a lot in people's
repositories. Technically, this
commit shouldn't be here,
because we shouldn't have made a
typo in the first place. So
comments like this are just
noise in the history. So later,
I will show you how to combine
these two commits to make our
history clean and readable. Look
at the next commit, change the
color of restaurant icons.
What's the problem with this?
Well, once again, this is part
of the same unit of work. So
ideally, we should combine all
these three commits into a
single logical commit. Next, we
have add a reference to Google
Map SDK, what do you think is
the problem with this commit,
the problem is the position of
this committee in the history
because here we are rendering
the restaurants on Google Map.
But then we're adding a
reference to Google Map over
here. So that means, if you
check out this committee on its
own, our application is not
going to work. Because at this
point in time, we don't have a
reference to Google Map. So here
we have two solutions, we should
either move this commit down and
put it before rendering
restaurants. Or we can combine
these two commits together.
After that we have a work in
progress commit. Again, very
common issue I see all the time.
Commits like this are just
oise in history. And later in
he future, let's say a week or
month from now, if we look at
ur history to see what was
hanged, and why we're not going
o extract meaningful
nformation from commits like
his. So we should either drop
his commit or change its
essage. Now look at the next
ommit, update Terms of Service
nd Google Map SDK. Here we have
commit that combines two
eparate kinds of changes,
pdating the terms of service
ot nothing to do with updating
oogle Map version. So ideally,
e should split this commit into
wo separate commits. Next, we
ave another work in progress
ommand, followed by a commit
ith a mysterious message. What
his period mean here, nobody
nows. So once again, we should
ither drop this commit or
hange this message. So
hroughout this section, I'm
oing to show you various tools
o clean up this history. We're
oing to start off by undoing
he last two commits. We'll do
hat next.