Let's say we decided that this
last commit over here is
useless. And we want to undo it.
Here we have two options. If you
have pushed this commit to a
remote repository, chances are
other people have based their
work on top of this commit. So
we shouldn't remove this commit.
Here, we should use the revert
command. And this will create a
new commit that will undo all
the changes in this commit. So
we type Git revert, head, and
we'll talk about this in more
detail in the next lesson. But
let's say we haven't pushed this
commit. So it only exists in our
local repository. Here, we can
use the reset command to remove
this commit from the history.
Now, I know that we have talked
about this before, but let's
revisit it one more time,
because I want to make sure you
really understand how it works.
So we type Git reset dash dash
heart, I'm going to talk about
this option in a second. And
then we type the target position
for our head pointer. So we want
to move the head pointer from
this commit to the commit
before. So we type head tilda
one. Now what is the hard
option? Well, let's say we have
two commits in our repository, A
and B. And B is the last commit,
because head is pointing to it.
Now look at our working
directory and the staging area.
In both these areas, we have the
same code that we have in our
last snapshot that is B. Now if
you reset the head using the
soft option, git will simply
move the head pointer to the
target location. But it's not
going to touch our staging area
and the working directory. Now,
what is this state? This is the
state before we committed B. So
we have some changes in our
working directory and the
staging area. But we haven't
committed those changes yet. So
this is the effect of the soft
option. If we use the mixed
option, it will take the latest
snapshot that is a and put it in
our staging area. What is this
date, this is the state before
we state our new changes. So we
have some new changes in our
working directory. But we
haven't staged those changes
yet. This is the effect of the
mixed option. Now if we use the
hard option, it will take the
latest snapshot and put it in
our working directory as well.
More accurately, it will put it
in both our working directory as
well as the staging area. So our
new changes in our working
directory are gone. So let me
show you a simple way to
understand and memorize the
difference between these
options. If we use the soft
option, git will only remove the
commit, but it's not going to
touch our staging area and the
working directory. So we're
going to have some changes in
the staging area ready to be
committed. If we use that mix
option, we go one step back. So
our changes in the staging area
will be unstaged. So we'll have
some local changes in our
working directory. And if we use
the heart option, we go even one
more step back. So good, we'll
discard our local changes. This
is how I've memorized the
difference between these
options. So let's see this in
action. Before resetting the
head. Let's look at the content
of the latest commit. So git
show head. And in our last
snapshot, we simply added the
word test in this file turns.
txt. Now let's reset the head
using the soft option. So our
last commit is going to go. But
this change is going to stay in
the staging area. So Git reset
dash dash soft head tilda one.
Alright, look, we have some
changes in our staging area, we
can verify it by getting a short
status. So you have a green
arrow, which means you have some
changes in terms of txt. Now we
can compare the staging area
with the latest snapshot using
the diff command. We talked
about this before. So git diff
dash dash cashed. So here's the
change in our staging area.
Beautiful. Now if we use the
mixed option, Git will unstag
our changes. So before running
git reset. Let's look at our lo
one more time. All right, look
head is currently pointing t
this commit. So our last comman
is gone. Now, let's type Gi
reset dash dash mixed head. Not
that I'm using head and not hea
tilda one because I want to k
ep head where it is. It's p
inting to this commit. So wh
n we use the mixed option, it wi
l take the snapshot that head po
nts to and put it in the st
ging area. So this is going to
unstaged changes, okay. And by
the way, mixed as the default op
ion so we don't have to type it
look good has unstaged ch
nges. So let's run a short st
tus. Now we have some changes in
our working directory. We can co
pare our working directory wi
h the staging area using the di
f command. So get diff wi
hout any arguments. There you go
So here's the change in our wo
king directory. Now if we use th
heart option, we go even one mo
e step back. So this local ch
nge will be gone. Git reset, da
h heart head. Our local ch
nge is gone and we have a clean
orking directory.