Let's see we have pushed all
these commits to a remote
repository. And now we want to
undo one or more of them. As I
explained before, resetting the
head is not an option here,
because we don't want to drop
the commits that we have shared
with others. So we have to use
the revert commit. Now let's say
we want to revert this commit
over here, we type Git revert
head, we can also revert an
earlier commit, like head to the
to, this will revert this commit
over here, we can also specify a
range. Let's say we want to
revert all the last three
commits. First, we'll look at
the parent of this commit. So
that is coming over here. So
here, we say revert had to the
Three, two head. And here's the
tricky part. When we say head to
the three to head, we're
referencing this range, but it
will actually revert the last
three commits. So it's not going
to include this commit over
here, okay? Now when we run this
command, Git is going to revert
each of these commits one by
one, take a look. Let's go.
Alright, first, it's going to
revert this commit, I'm going to
keep the default message as is.
So let's close this window. Now,
Git is reversing the next
commit. Once again, I'm going to
keep the default message. So
let's move on. And here's one
more revert operation. Let's go.
Alright, reverting is done. Now
let's look at our history. Look,
we have three revert commits.
And this is very ugly, it's
adding so much noise in our
history. Wouldn't it be better
if you reverted all these
commits using a single commit,
let me show you how to do that.
First, I want to reset the head
to this position to get rid of
this revert commits. So Git
reset dash dash heart had tilde
three. Let's look at our history
one more time. So we're in the
same state as before, and we
want to revert the last three
commits, we type Git revert,
we're going to use an option
called no commit. With this
ption, it will simply add the
equired changes in the staging
rea. So for every commit that
e're going to revert, it will
igure out the changes that need
o be undone, then it will appl
those changes in the stagin
area. Just like before, we'r
going to specify our range, s
head tilda three to head. Now,
we can simplify this by dropping
the second hat. So with this,
we're essentially reverting the
last three commits, take a look.
So get removed this file,
because we added this file in
one of the last three commits.
Now look, we have some changes
in our staging area. So git
status, dash s. Here's the
reverse of all the changes
across the last three commits.
f you screwed something, and we
ant to get out of this date, we
an type Git revert, abort. Or
f we're happy with our changes,
e can use the continue option.
ow in this case, I don't want
o accept the default message,
ecause we're reverting multiple
ommits. So we should write a
essage that better describes
he commits that we're
everting. In this demo, I'm
oing to say revert bad code.
ave close. All right, reverting
s done. Let's look at our
istory. Now we have a single
referred commit beautiful, so
e can push this to the origin
nd share it with others.