Sometimes we may screw up while
resetting the head. Let me give
you an example. So here's our
history, I'm going to run git
reset hard head, tilda six,
let's say this is an accident.
Now, let's bring up the history
again, what happened to our
commits? You may think that we
have lost our commits, well,
I've got a good news for you.
With git, we don't really lose
anything, all the information
about our project history, all
the commits that we have
created, all of these objects
are stored in our repository,
even if we don't see them when
looking at the history. So Git
keeps on these objects for a
while. And if they're not used
anymore, then it will garbage
collector. So how can we recover
the lost commit? Well, we have a
great tool here called ref log.
And this is basically a log of
how a reference has moved in our
history. If it don't supply any
options here, I guess we'll show
how the head pointer has moved
in our history. Take a look.
Now, you might think this looks
like a scary movie. But trust
me, this is easier than you
think. So from the top, look at
the first entry. And this lock.
Every entry has a unique
identifier. Here's the unique
identifier of the first entry.
Here's the unique identifier of
the second entry. Now in front
of the unique identifier, we see
a description of what happened.
So just a few seconds ago, we
used the reset operation to mov
the head to this new position
Now after this operation, now
head is pointing to this commen
over here, we can verify it. S
we've got our history. hat i
here, and it's pointing to thi
commit af 26. We can verify i
here. Now look at the secon
entry in the lock. Before ther
was an operation, we made
commit with this message, rever
bad code. After this operation
the head pointer was at thi
location. So to recover the las
commit, we can reset the hea
back to this location. So I'
going to copy this. Here we ca
use the command ID or the uniqu
identifier of this entry. So w
type Git reset hard. In thi
demo, I'm going to use the entr
ID. Good. Now head is at thi
location called revert bac
code. Let's look at our histor
one more time. All our commit
are back beautiful. Now we ca
use the ref log to see how othe
pointers have more than ou
history. So let's say we have
branch called feature. We ca
type Git ref log show featur
and this will show the histor
of the feature pointe