There are a lot of cases where
we make a commit. But then we
realized that we made a mistake,
perhaps we left a typo, or we
accidentally included a file in
our commit. In these situations,
we don't really need to make
another commit, we can amend or
modify the last commit, let me
show you. So let's echo cafes to
map. txt. Now, let's make a
commit. And say, render cafes on
the map. Good. Now, let's say we
made a mistake. And we should
have echoed blue cafes on map
dot txt. So let's open map.txt
and make the required changes,
blue cafes. Good. Now, back in
the terminal, first, we need to
a stage the changes. So git add,
period. Good. Now to amend the
last commit, we type git commit
dash dash MN, we can supply a
new message, or I can just enter
and accept the previous message.
I'm happy with the message. So
let's close this back in the
terminal. Our last commit is
Amanda. Just remember, we didn't
really modify the last commit.
Because as I told you before,
commits and Git are immutable.
So even though on the surface we
amended the last commit, git
actually created a new commit.
Okay, now, let's look at the
history. So here's our last
commit. Let's look at the
content of this commit. So git
show head. Take a look. Now w
have blue cafe's. As anothe
example, let's say we forgot t
include a file and the las
commit. How can we do that? Th
exact same way. So I'm going t
echo hello to file one dot txt
Now, let's stage the changes
And amend the last commit. We'r
going to accept the sam
message. So let's move on. Now
Let's look at the history on
more time. Here's our las
commit, we didn't add a
additional commit. Let's look a
the content of the last commit
So here we have two changes. W
introduced a new file, file on
dot txt with this content. An
we added this new line to map
txt. Perfect. Now let's say
e accidentally included file o
e.txt in the last commit, how c
n we remove it? Well, earlier w
talked about resetting the h
ad, I talked about three
ifferent options, soft, mixed
nd hard. I told you that if we
se the mixed option, it is
oing to unstaged our changes,
ut all of our changes are going
o stay in our working
irectory. So I'm going to reset
he head using the mixed option
o head tilda one now our wor
ing directory is dirty. So let
s run a short status. We hav
two changes. We have some mod
fications to map dot txt, and
a new untracked file. Let's say
we don't need file one. So we
an run git clean fd. We talk
d about this earlier in the cour
e. With this we can remove untr
cked files from our working dire
tory. Alright, so file one is g
ne. And we are left with the
hanges in map dot txt. So let'
stage two changes, and then
ake a commit. Here, I'm not g
ing to use them at option becau
e we've removed the last commi
by resetting the head point
r. So here we should creat
a new commit and say render
cafe's on the map. So this i
how we can amend the last c
mmit. But how can we amend
n earlier commit? We'll talk a
out that next.