Let's see how we can amend an
earlier commit. So look at this
commit over here, add a
reference to Google Map SDK.
Before going further, let's look
at the contents of this command.
So I'm going to copy the command
ID. Now let's run, get show. So
in this commit, we're adding
this line to package dot txt.
Now let's say we forgot to
include the license for Google
Map. So we want to go back in
history and amend this commit.
Now, let's pull up the history
one more time. So to edit this
commit, we're going to use
interactive rebasing, as you
learned earlier in the course,
with rebasing, we can replay a
bunch of commits on top of
another commit. So here, we're
going to replay this commit, and
all the future commits on top of
the parent of this commit, which
is this commit over here. So I
want to copy this commit idea.
Now, let's run git rebase dash I
for interactive, this basically
means that we're going to
interact with the rebase
operation. So we're going to
stop it, make changes and
continue. Now we paste the
commit ID. All right, take a
look. What we have here is a
scrip, it contains a series of
instructions about the rebase
operation. So here we have
instructions or commands like
pick. Down here, you can see a
legend of all the supported
commands. So we have pick,
reward, edit, and so on. As we
go through the section, you're
gonna learn more about these
commands. So in the script, we
have all the comments are you
going to replay listed from the
oldest to the newest. So up here
as the commit that you're going
to edit, and down here is the
latest commit. Now, I'm going to
change this instruction from
pick to edit, we can also edit
multiple commits if you want to,
in this demo, I'm going to edit
only a single commit. So revert
and save the changes. Now at
this point, you know that when
you edit a commit, git actually
creates a new commit. Here's the
interesting part. In this demo,
even though we're editing only a
single commit, all the commits
that come after this commit will
also be edited, or more
accurately recreated. Let me
explain why. Imagine we have
four commits in our history. And
we want to amend B. Git creates
a new commit, let's call that B
star. Now, C should point to B
star, right? But this is not
possible. Because commits are
immutable. So the parent of C
cannot be changed. In the
situation, git creates another
commit that looks exactly like
C, but he points to B star. By
the same token, it will create
another commit that looks like
D, but points to C star. So even
though we only modified B, all
the subsequent commits had to be
modified or more accurately
recreated. So remember, rebasing
is a destructive operation,
because it rewrites history. So
you should use it only for the
commits that you haven't shared
with others. Okay. All right
back to our script, we're going
to edit the first commit in this
lesson. Now, when we close this
window, the rebase operation
will start back in the terminal,
take a look, you've stopped at
this commit, add a reference to
oogle Map SDK. So because we
old gate that we want to edit
his commit, get stopped here.
ow we have a chance to amend
his commit. So we're going to
ake the necessary changes,
hen, we're going to amend this
ommit, and then continue with t
e rebase operation. So I'm g
ing to echo license to license d
t txt and add this change and a
end the current commit. And w
're going to accept the p
evious message. That's good. N
w, back in the terminal, we m
de a new commit. Now, let's ru
git log, one line, all graph an
let's see what's going on he
e. We have two branches. In th
s branch, we have all the co
mits that we wanted to re
lay. Down here is the first co
mit that is to commit that we
anted to edit. We modified thi
commit and git created anot
er commit with the same messa
e up here. The rebasing opera
ions stop. So once we conti
ue rebasing, all the subse
uent commits will be replay
d on top of this new commit
and then this branch will b
discarded, take a look. So we
ype Git rebase dash dash contin
e, or if we screw up, we can al
ays abort the rebase operat
on and go back to the previo
s state before we started the re
ase. So let's continue rebasi
g. Good. Now let's look at the l
g one more time. We have a simpl
, clean history. If you paid
lose attention, you proba
ly noticed that the commit IDs a
e different. So here's the new i
ea of the commit that we chang
d. Let's copy this and run git s
ow. So now in this commi
tee, we have two changes. We in
roduced a new file, licen
ed .txt, and we added this line
to package .txt perfect Now let
me show you something interes
ing. I'm going to pull up the
istory one more time.
So we added licensed. txt in thi
commit. Now what if we check ou
the commit that was introduce
later, let's say this commit. I
we check this out, you will se
that our license file is stil
there, even though it was not i
the original work in progres
commit. So let's check out thi
commit. The head pointer i
detached. Now, let's look at th
files in our project. Here's th
license file that we just added
So here's what you need to tak
away the change that w
introduced in one of the earlie
commits carried on throughou
the rest of the history
Alright, we're done here. S
let's check out maste