In this section, we'll look at
various ways to browse the
history of our project, you will
learn how to search for commits
by author, date, message,
content, and so on. We'll also
talk about viewing a commit to
see what files have been changed
and how. Next I'll show you how
to restore your project to an
earlier point in time to the
snapshot stored in one of your
commits. We'll also see how we
can compare a commit to see what
files have been changed and how
you will also learn to view the
history of a file to see how
it's evolved from day one, and
who has written each line of
code. And finally, I'll show you
a great tool for quickly finding
a bad commit that introduced a
bug in your application. So
there's a lot we're going to
cover. Let's jump in and get
started.