Sometimes we need to find all
the people who have contributed
to our project, we have a
special command for that get
short log. so here we can see
y name, the number of commits
've created, and a summary of
ommit messages. Here we have
arious interesting options. So
et's run git short log dash H.
or example, we can use dash n
r dash dash numbered, whatever
ou prefer. to sort the output
ased on the number of commits
er author, we can use dash s to
uppress commit descriptions,
nd dash E to show email a
dresses. For example, we can s
y get short log dash n. Now t
is is sorted based on the n
mber of commits per author. In t
is repository, we have a s
ngle author, so the output d
esn't really change, but we c
n add a dash s to suppress the c
mmit messages. Now we can only s
e the number of commits per a
thor. Now in addition to this, w
can pass dash e to the email a
dress of each author. So with t
is we can easily find the most a
tive contributors. Here we can a
so filter the list for e
ample, we can use before and o
after options that we talked a
out earlier, to view the c
ntributors per given date r
nge.