Let's see how we can view the
history of a file. For example,
we have this file here, table of
content dot txt, let's find all
the commits that have touched
this file. So we run git log
table of content, the txt. If
this is too verbose, we can use
the one line option. That's
better. Now we can find
statistics about each commit in
terms of the number of changes
using the stat option. We have
seen this before. Now we know in
this commit, we have one
insertion and one deletion. In
this other commit, we have more
changes. So then we can view
that particular commit in
detail. If we want to see the
actual changes in each commit,
we can use the patch option. So
instead of stop use patch. Now
we know in this command, which
is our last command, this line
was removed and replaced by
blackline. In the other command,
before that, we added these few
lines and so on. So to view the
history of a file, we still use
the lock command, but we append
the file name at the end