We all make mistakes, sometimes
we may accidentally delete a
file. So let me show you how to
recover a deleted file from the
history. For this demo, I'm
going to remove the table of
content file. So we're going to
use the rm command or move to C
dot txt. Now we have a change,
let's commit it and say, remove
table of contents. txt. Now this
message is purely for this demo,
in a real situation, the message
is not going to indicate that
we're deleting a file because
that would happen accidentally.
So we may remove this file as
part of fixing a bug or
implementing a new feature.
Okay, so our table of content
file has gone. Now we need to
find all the commits that have
touched this file. So we run git
log one line, toc dot txt, the
here we get this fatal error
saying ambiguous argument, table
of contents. txt, this is one of
those situations where I told
you, it is not able to properly
interpret your file name. So you
have to separate it from the
options using double hyphens. So
we bring up the last command and
add double hyphens here. So here
are all the commits that have
touched this file. Obviously,
the last commit is the one that
has deleted this file, because
we don't have any further
changes to that file after that
commit. So now, to restore this
file, we have to look at the
parent of this commit, which is
this commit over here, this is
where we had the latest version
of this file. Because in this
commit over here, our table of
content file was deleted. So it
doesn't exist in this snapshot.
So we look at this parent, we
take this ID and now we're going
to check out only the table of
content file from this commit.
So git checkout commit, and then
we add the past to our file. So
our working directory is dirty.
Let's run a short status. We
have one new file that is also
in the staging area. So let's
commit it and say restore ta
le of content dot txt. This is
how we can restore a deleted fi
e.