Another useful tool in Git is
the blame tool. With this, we
can find the author of a
particular line. So as part of
troubleshooting issues, we may
wonder who has written that
terrible, smelly, disgusting
line of code. That's where we
use the blame tool to basically
blame them for writing that
piece of code. Here's an
example. Get blame audience dot
txt. Now, in front of each line
of code in this file, we have
some extra pieces of
information, we can see the
commit where this line was
inserted, we can see the
author's name and the date and
time this line was inserted. Now
if we want to find the author's
email, we use the dash E,
option, dash E and set up the
name we have the email, we can
also filter by lines. So if you
have a large file, we don't want
to see all these details. Let's
say we're only interested in the
first three lines. So we type
Git blame dash, capital L, and
here we say one, comma three.
Now we only see the first three
lines.