Quite often, we need to bookmark
certain points in the history of
our project, like the commit
that represents a given version,
we use tags for this purpose,
let me show you how this works.
So let's say this code over
here, the last commit represents
the first version of our
software. So we can give it a
tag or a custom label. So we
type Git tag, version 1.0. Now,
if you want to tag an earlier
commit, we have to type the
commit ID or the commit hash
here, like 5 E 78828. Now, le
's look at our log again. So lo
k, in front of this commit, we h
ve a tag a label, we can refere
ce this commit using the tag. So
if you want to check out t
is commit, we can say git check
ut version 1.0, exactly the s
me way with check out a com
it using its ID. But instead of
he ID, we use this tag, or t
is custom label. Now, to see
ll the tags we have created, t
pe git tag. Currently, we hav
a single tag, this tag that
we have created is what we cal
a lightweight tag. It's jus
a reference or a pointer t
a particular commit. But again,
we have another type of tag cal
ed annotated tag, which i
a complete object with a bunch
of properties, like tagger na
e, email, and message. So if
ou want to create an annotated t
g, we type Git tag, dash a
or annotated, then we type the
ag name, like version 1.1. And h
re we need to supply a messa
e, just like creating a commit.
So we can say, my version on po
nt one, of course, this message
is redundant, there is no po
nt having this message. But
he idea is that with annota
ed tags, we can associate a mess
ge with a tag. Now, let's look
at the list of tags. So git t
g. Currently, we have two tags,
we don't see their messages. To
ee the message we type Git tag d
sh n. So here's our first t
g, which is a lightweight tag,
he message associated with this
ag is actually the message of
he commit that it points to.
In contrast, here's our annota
ed tag, which has a custom messa
e. Now let's look at the second
ag we just created. Git s
ow version 1.1. So on the top,
we have some information about t
is tag, we can see the tags n
me and email, the date and time
he tag was created, as well as
he custom message we provid
d. Below that we have the f
ll details of the commit. So qu
te often we prefer annotated t
gs to lightweight tags. Now,
to delete a tag, we type Git
ag dash D and the type of tag na
e. The tag is gone. So we have o
ly a single tag in our reposito