Let's see how we can use VS code
to view the history of our
project. To do that, you have to
install an extension called
GitLens. So go to the extensions
panel and search for GitLens.
It's right here. This is a very
popular extension, look at the
number of downloads, it's over 6
million times. So once you
install this, you're going to
see a new icon over here. That
is GitLens. Now on the top,
let's go to repositories. Here's
our Venice repository. And we're
currently on the master branch.
Let's open the master branch.
Here are the commits on this
branch. For each commit, we can
see the message we can see the
author and we can see the number
of files that were added,
modified, and deleted. Now if we
expand any of these commits, we
can see all the files that were
changed in that commit. If we
click on any of these files, we
can see a diff of the changes.
So this line was removed. And
these two lines were added.
Pretty helpful. Now, let me
close the master branch. So over
here, we can see all the
branches, we have, we'll look at
branches. In the next section,
we can see the contributors. So
here are all the people who have
contributed to this repository.
In this case, I'm listed twice,
because I've created some of
these commits on another machine
with a different email. So that
is why I'm listed twice here.
Now, we also have our tags.
Currently, we have a single tag,
version 1.0 that is referencing
this commit. Now let's look at
some File History. So this File
History panel works when we have
a file open in the editor. So
I'm going to open our table of
content file. Now back to
GitLens. In a File History
panel, we can see all the
commits that have touched this
file. Once again, if you click
on any of this commits, we can
see the lines that were added or
deleted. Now let's see how we
can compare commits. So we click
on this, we have to select two
commits. Here, we can type a
commit ID or a relative
reference using head I want to
comprehend with head till
they're six. So these are all
the files that have been changed
across these two commits. If you
click on any of these files, we
can see the exact lines are
added or deleted. Now let's look
at search commands. So we can
search by message, author commit
ID files, or changes. So let's
search by a message. So after
message for type, a keyword,
let's say GUI. This is the only
commit that has the word GUI in
its message. Now earlier in the
course, I told you that all
these GUI tools have some
limitations. For example, here,
we cannot apply a second filter,
we can only search by a single
filter, like message, author,
and so on. If I have so many
commits with a particular
keyword in their message, and
then I want to filter the range
to a particular date range, I
cannot do that here, I have to
go back to the terminal. Another
limitation we have here is the
lack of bisect command, so we
cannot use bisect to quickly
find a bad commit. For that,
again, we have to go back to the
terminal. That is the reason why
I'm personally not a fan of GUI
tools, I prefer to do things
mostly on the terminal. GUI
tools are great for diffing s
eing exactly how the code is m
dified from one commit to a
other. Now, one last thing b
fore we finish this lesson, l
t me show you how to create a
d delete tags. So we have to
ring up the command palette. On
ac the shortcut is shift
ommand and P and on Windows is
robaby shift control NP. If t
is doesn't work on your m
chine, go to the View menu on t
e top and find the command p
lette. It's the first item. U
fortunately, it's not visible i
my recording window right n
w. So let's bring up the c
mmand palette, and type get t
g. Now we can see all the c
mmands related to tags. So we c
n create, delete, or push t
gs. We'll talk about pushing t
gs in the future. So let's c
eate a tag. We give it a name, l
t's say version 1.2. We type a m
ssage. And now we have a new t
g associated with the latest c
mmit. So if you go to r
positories, and tags, here's o
r tag. If you want to create a t
g for an earlier commit, you h
ve to find that commit first. S
let's say we want to add a t
g to this commit right here. W
right click and select Create t
g.