Let's see how we can browse the
history using GitKraken. So
first we go to open a
repository, we go to our project
directory, and open our
repository. So here's the
history of our project, we can
clearly see all the commits we
have created so far. On the left
side, we can see our pointers.
So master branch is just a
pointer to the last commit over
here. Next to master we have
plus one, which means we have
another pointer pointing to the
same commit, take a look, that
is our tag, version 1.2, we have
another tag pointing to this
commit. Now we can search for
commits right here. And here we
can find commits by their ID,
author, or message. So if I type
GUI, this is the only commit t
at has the word GUI in this mes
age. As I told you before, all
these GUI tools have some lim
tations. For example, here, we
annot find commits created by
given author in a par
icular date range, so we can
ot apply multiple filters. In
hose situations, we just hav
to go back to the terminal. Now
we can select any of this com
its to see its details. So her
on the right side, we can see
the commit ID, message, aut
or, as well as the summary of m
dified files. So here, we have m
dified five files, we can see a
l these files listed here, we c
n sort the list in ascending o
descending order, we can see t
e list in the tree structure o
in a flat list. Now we have a v
ry useful option here, view a
l files. So if this commit has m
dified only two files, but you w
nt to look at the other files i
a project, at that point in tim
, we can select this and ope
any of these files. For exa
ple, here, sales page, that txt
hasn't been modified. That's why
we don't have an icon next to
t. But we can click on it to see
what it looked like at that poi
t in time. Now, let's look at
ur table of content file. So her
's the final version of this fil
storage and this command to see
the actual changes, we go to the
diff View tab. So you can see
this line was removed and rep
aced by a blank line. I totally
ove the diff view in GitKra
en and it makes our job a lot ea
ier. You also have two tabs he
e, blame and history, which ki
d of brings us to the same vi
w, let me show you. So we can go
to history. Here on the left, yo
can see all the commits that ha
e touched this file, here's th
first commit. And here's the la
t commit. So as we look at th
s commit, we can see how thi
file has evolved. So let's cha
ge the diff view to file vie
. In the first commit, our fil
was empty. And the second com
it, we added this lines. And in
he last commit, we removed the
border under the header. Now if
ou click on the blame tab her
, unfortunately, it's not vis
ble in my recording window.
But if you click on it, we can t
ggle blame details. So this
ine was added in this commi
over here by this person
So we can clearly see who ha
written what line of code.
ow let's close this window
And this window as well. Back t
our history, let's see how we
can compare two commits. So I'm
going to compare this commit
with this commit over here.
o select the second commit
we press Command on Mac, or Ctr
on Windows. Now on the right
ide, you can see we have select
d two commit. And here are the f
les that have been changed acros
these two commits. So this
s how we can compare commi
s. Now, if you right click on an
of this commits, we can check
ut that commit. All right,
now look, the head pointe
is pointing to this commit
so it's in the detached state.
Now to attach it back to the ma
ter branch, we right click
he master branch and go to che
kout master. Good. Now one mo
e thing here, we can right
lick a commit and create a tag
r an annotated tag. We have a
bunch of other commands here.
e'll talk about them in the fu
ure. So this is how we can br
wse the history and get cracki
g. That before we finish this l
sson, let me show you anothe
useful feature here. We can br
ng up the command palette by pre
sing Command and P on Mac, o
Ctrl, and P on Windows, the his
ory of various commands, we can
select the blame command. And
then here we can search for a f
le in our project, let's say tab
e of contents. txt. So we hav
auto completion. This is fan
astic. I love it. So let's loo
at table of content. Now we can
see the full history of this fil
, we can see we accidentally del
ted this file and this com
it, and then added it back ove
here. And of course, if we tog
le the blame details, we can see
who has written what line of cod
very handy. Now let's bring up
he command palette one more tim
. We can also search for com
its. So we can search by mess
ge like GUI, or by author, or b
commit ID and so on. Withi
the command palette, we can a
so create tags. So let's searc
for tag. Now we can creat
a tag. This will create a tag f
r the last commit in our repos
tory. To create a tag for an ea
lier commit. As I told you,
e have to right click that commi
and go to create tag.