The first thing we're going to
look at is the lock command that
you learned about in the
previous section. In this
lesson, we're going to study
this command in a bit more
detail. So here in the Venus
directory, let's run git log. so
here we can see all the commits
in this repository. For each
commit, we can see its unique
identifier or hash, we can see
its author, the author, name,
and email, the date and time it
was created, and the one liner
message or subject. Now by
default, all these commits are
listed from the newest to the
oldest. So here's our last
commit. Now, because we have
multiple pages here, we can
press space to go to the next
page, we can also use the up and
down arrows to go up and down
like this. Now to quit, we press
Q. Okay. Now let's look at some
of the interesting options of
this command. So git log, one of
them that you already know is
one line, which gives us a
summary of all his commands, we
can add additional options here.
For example, if you want to see
all the files that have been
changed in each commit, we can
use the stat option, take a
look. So in our last commit,
five files have been changed.
Here, you can see the name of
these files, we have audience
dot txt, objectives and so on.
In front of each file, you can
see the number of changes. So
for audience dot txt, we have
four changes, we have three
insertions and one deletion. So
three lines were inserted and
one line was deleted. In total,
five files have been changed.
several lines have been inserted
and four lines have been
deleted. Now, we don't
necessarily have to use this
option with the one line option.
For example, we can run git log
stat. Now we have the full
details about each commit. Okay?
Now what if you want to see the
actual changes in each commit,
we can use the patch option. So
git log, I'm going to use one
line and then patch. So in our
last commit, here, we can see a
diff of audience dot txt. So
hese two lines were inserted.
his line was removed, and then
his line was added. Right after
hat we have a diff of another
ile. So for each file, we can
ee exactly what lines have been
hanged and in the next lesson,
'm going to show you how to
ilter the history