In this repository, we have just
over 10 commits. But in a real
repository, we often have
hundreds or sometimes thousands
of commits, depending on the age
of the repository. Now, we don't
have to look at all of these
commits. So let me show you a
few different ways to filter the
history. We can filter it by
author, by date, by commit
message, by content, and so on.
So let's run git log one line.
Now, if you want to see the last
three commands, we simply type
dash three here. There you go.
Now we can also filter by
author. So one line, here, type
dash dash author, equals, and
here in double quotes, we type
the author's name, let's say
Mosh. So here are all the
commits that I have submitted to
this repository, we can also
filter by date. So instead of
author we can use before and or
after. So we can say, hey, show
me all the commits from 2020. On
August 17. This will return all
the commits created on this
date. And after, take a look. We
can also specify relative dates,
that is pretty useful. For
example, we can say, hey, show
me all the commits from
yesterday. Or we can say, show
me all the commits from one week
ago, or two days ago, or one
month ago. pretty useful. We can
also filter by commit message or
subject. For example, we can
say, hey, show me all the
commits that have the word GUI
and their message, k type, dash
dash, grab, equals. And here in
double quotes, we type the
search term GUI, just remember
that this operation is case
sensitive. So if we type GUI in
lowercase, we're going to have a
different result. Take a look.
Here, we have only a single
commit that has the word GUI and
a subject. We can also filter
the history by content, let's
say we want to find all the
commits that have added or
removed a function declaration.
So we type, instead of dash dash
grab, we're going to type dash,
capital S. And here, we're not
going to use an equal sign.
Instead, we're going to add
double quotes. And in between
the quotes, we're going to type
our function name, let's say,
all the commits that have added
or remove this line. Now, this
repository, we don't have any
code, we just have plain
English. So let's find all the
commits that have added the word
objectives in capital. There you
go, here's the commit. Now, if
you want to see the actual
changes in this commit, we can
use the patch option, you learn
about it in the last video. So
we bring up the last command.
And then at the end, we type
dash dash patch. So in this
commit, this file was modified
object dot txt, and over here,
you can see that object is was
inserted, very useful. We can
also filter the history by a
range of commits. So let me
bring up all the commands. Let's
say we are only interested in
the commits in a particular
range here, let's say from this
commit to this commit over here.
So we can say git log one line.
Here, we add the first commit
hash, so FB, 0 d 184. Then we
add double periods. And then we
type the target commit ID, like
EDB 3594. Now what if you want
to find all the commits that
touch a particular file or a
bunch of files? Well, that is
super easy. We simply type git
log, we can optionally use one
line, it's not compulsory. Now
if you want to find all the
commits that have modified our
table of content file, we simply
add the file name at the end. So
these three commands have
modified this file. Now
sometimes, depending on the name
of your files, it might complain
and say, Hey, this name is
ambiguous. In those cases, we
have to separate the file name
from the options over here. So
we bring up the last command.
And here we use double hyphens
to separate the file name. From
the options we're using here.
You don't have to use this all
the time, you have to use this
only if we get complaints about
he file name saying, hey, this
is ambiguous and I cannot fig
re out what options you're usi
g. So in this case, we get the s
me result. Now if you want to
ee the actual changes in each
of these commits, once again, we
can use the patch option. Howe
er, the patch option shoul
be listed before the filename s
we cannot add it over here.
t's not going to work. Because
now after we added double hyp
ens get is interpreting this
s a file name. And there is no
uch a file called dash dash pa
ch. So to make this work, we hav
to use the patch op
over here.
Now for each command, we can see
the actual changes in our table
of content file.