So here's the default output of
the log command. Now, if this is
not what you want, and you don't
like the one line option,
either, you can easily customize
the output of the log command.
Let me show you how. So we type
Git log, dash dash, pretty
equals format, colon, double
quotes. I know this is a little
bit long. But the good thing is
you don't have to memorize any
of these things, you can always
go back to the documentation or
look at the cheat sheet that
I've provided for you. So here
in double quotes, we can specify
a format string, this format
string can be a combination of
plaintext, and some placeholders
that will get replaced by git to
display pieces of information
about each commit. For example,
if I type Hello here, for each
commit, we see the word hello,
of course, this is useless. So
here, we want to display
information dynamically. Let's
bring up this command one more
time. And after the word hello,
type percent, a n, which is
short for author name. Now take
a look. For each commit, we can
see the author name, right after
the word hello.
Let's make this more
interesting.
So I'm going
to remove hello and say, person
am I committed now here we want
to display the commit ID or
hash, so use percent capital H.
Now we can see the author name,
right after that see committed
and here's the full hash for
each commit. This is too
verbose. So we can use the
lowercase h to see the
abbreviation
like this.
That is better.
If you look at the documentation
for the log command, somewhere
in the middle of the page, you
can see the complete list of
these placeholders. So we have
capital H, for displaying the
commit hash, or lowercase h for
displaying the abbreviated
commit hash, we have quite a few
other placeholders. So back to
the terminal. Let's take this to
the next level. So right after
the hash we can say on and here
we can display the date, percent
CD, that is commit date. There
you go. So you can customize the
output of the lock command any
way that suits your needs. Now
we can also colorize this
output. For example, we can
display the author name in
green. Let me show you how to do
this. So we bring up the last
command. Just before the author
name, we type percent, capital
C, and then lowercase green.
Look, here we have two
placeholders. The first
placeholder
is for changing the color. And
the second placeholder is for
displaying the author name. Now,
everything comes out in green,
because we didn't change the
color after displaying the
author name. So let's bring up
the last command. Right after
the author name, we can type
percent, capital C, and the
lowercase reset. That's much
better. Similarly, we can use a
different color for the commit
ID, and the date or other pieces
of information we have here.
Once again, back to the
documentation for the log
ommand. Here you can see
arious placeholders for
hanging the color. So we have
, red, C, green, C Blue C reset
and C in parenthesis, we can
supply a custom color. Now in
eality, you're not going to rem
mber all these details every ti
e when I look at the history. So
in the next lesson, I'm going to
show you how to create an al
as for this long command.