In Git, we can easily set up
aliases for the commands that we
use frequently. So we don't have
to type them in their long form.
Let me show you. So we type Git
config, dash dash global. So
this configuration gets applied
to all of our repositories. Here
in the alias section, we're
going to define a new property.
So we type a period. And then we
type a custom command name, for
example, LG. And in short for
lock. Now whenever we type git
LG, we won't get to execute a
particular get command. So we
type that command here, log dash
dash pretty. Now because we have
a space here, we should wrap
this value with double quotes.
Okay, so pretty equals format
colon, here, we have to use
double quotes again, to specify
a format string. But because we
have already surrounded the
value with double quotes, I'm
going to replace the inner
quotes with single quotes. Okay,
so here we can say percent as an
as an author name, committed
percent H, so here's the result.
Now, let's open up our global
configuration file in our
default editor. So type Git
config, dash dash global dash E.
So here's our Git config file.
Now, down here, in the alias
section, we have the LG command
that is bound to log with this
pretty format. So now if we
close this, and type get LG, we
see the output our custom log
ommand. aliases are very
seful. But in this course, I'm
ot going to use them because if
omeone watches the course from
he middle, I don't want them to
onder what is this custom git
ommand that is not documented
nywhere. Okay. Before we finish
his lesson, let me give you
nother useful example of an
lias. So let's define another
lias called on stage. With this
e can easily onstage the
hanges. So we're going to bind
his to the Restore command in g
t once again, use double q
otes. Here we type restore, d
sh dash staged period. With t
is, you're going to restore a
l the files in the staging a
ea. Now we can easily type git o
stage. As simple as that.