Now let's see how we can view a
commit. We talked about this
briefly in the previous section.
But let's explore it in a bit
more detail now. So let's say we
want to view this commit over
here, there are two ways to
reference this commit, we can
use the commit ID, or we can use
a relative reference using the
head pointer. So as we can see,
head is in front of the last
commit. And this commit we're
interested in, is two commits
before the last commit. So we
can type git show head Tilda
two, that means go to the head,
which is the last commit, and
then go two steps back. So here,
we can see all the details about
this commit, we can see the
commit ID or commit hash, the
author of the commit, the date
and time, the subject, and a
diff of every file that has
changed in this commit. In this
case, only a single file has
been changed. And that is this
file over here, staging changes
dot txt. In this file, we have
two new lines, as we can see
over here, now what if we don't
want to see the changes, we want
to see the final version of a
file in this commit? Well, we
bring up the last command, then
we add a colon. And here we type
the past to our file. So this
file we're interested in is in a
directory called sections. Here
we have another directory called
creating dash snapshots. And our
file is called staging. Dash
changes, a txt. So here's the
final version of this file
stored in this commit. Now, what
if we don't want to see the
actual changes or the actual
lines of code in this commit, we
just want to see the files that
have been modified in this
commit. Well, we type Git show
head tilda two and then we us
an option called name dash on
y. So over here, we can see al
the files that have been ad
ed, modified or deleted in th
s commit. With this option, we
can only see the name of the fi
e, so we cannot tell which fi
es have been added, modified or
deleted. To get that in
ormation, we have to use a di
ferent option called name da
h status. So now we have the le
ter M here, which means this fi
e has been modified