Now what if we want to see the
changes across two commits. For
example, let's say we want to
know what has been changed over
the last three commits. To do
that, we're going to use the
diff command. In the previous
section, you'll learn how to use
the diff command to view the
staged and unstaged changes. Now
we're going to use the same
command to see the differences
between two commits. So we can
start from head tilda two and go
to head and now we can see a
diff of every file that has been
changed across these two
commits. So here we have a diff
of audience txt. Below that we
can see the changes in
objectives or txt and so on. If
you want to see the changes to a
particular file, you can add the
file name at the end. so here we
can type audience dot txt. Now
we only see the changes in this
file. Also, similar to the lock
command. Here we have options
like name, status, and name only
to view the list of files that
have been changed. So we can say
name only to see the list of
files that have been changed, or
we can say name status, to see
the list of files, or the type
of change. In this case, we only
have modifications, but if you
had new or deleted files, they
would be listed here as well.